<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>YourStory.com</title>
	<atom:link href="http://yourstory.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://yourstory.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 10:39:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>3 tips for better cash management at your startup</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/cash-management-tips-startup/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/cash-management-tips-startup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 07:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Varun Rathi]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Backburner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business incubators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decluttr Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASSCOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[welcomed technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176751</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There has never been a better time to start your own business venture in India.  The past year has witnessed the country transforming into a hotbed of entrepreneurial activity, owing to progressive initiatives mooted by the Central and State governments. According to NASSCOM, a whopping 40 percent growth will make India a haven to more [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There has never been a better time to start your own business venture in India.  The past year has witnessed the country transforming into a hotbed of entrepreneurial activity, owing to progressive initiatives mooted by the Central and State governments. According to <a href="http://tech.firstpost.com/news-analysis/india-youngest-startup-nation-80000-jobs-created-nasscom-india-startup-report-284520.html" target="_blank">NASSCOM</a>, a whopping 40 percent growth will make India a haven to more than 4,200 startups by the end of the year. However, one question persists: despite having a conducive environment to grow and thrive,  why do a majority of small businesses struggle to keep their heads above the water? If one scratches the surface, it is easy to see that <em>the real challenges to staying afloat in the face of adversity is, in fact, intrinsic to the organisation</em>.</p>
<p>Amidst the excitement of daily business operations, it is easy for small business owners to underestimate the importance of processes such as cash management, and put them on the backburner. The consequences present themselves quickly: entrepreneurs are left empty-handed when they need to pay their employees and vendors, and sometimes their own personal bills.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Maths-money-YourStory.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-156542" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Maths-money-YourStory.jpg" alt="Maths-money---YourStory" width="800" height="400" /></a></p>
<p>Though idle petty cash accounts for only 1 to 3 percent of total current assets, it is imperative that it does not dry up. Like blood in the human body, there has to be a constant flow in order to sustain the business at all times. At every step of the way, startups need to be prepared for financial curveballs that appear in the garb of delayed invoicing and disbursements, indefinite floats and flawed go-to-market strategies. Operating in a region where Cash On Delivery (COD) has become the preferred mode of payment also adds more perplexing challenges to the mix. Only a handful of startups are getting it right, and live to tell the story.</p>
<h2><strong>Cash management 101</strong></h2>
<p>Though critical, this practice is not as complicated and alarming as we have historically been led to believe. It is actually quite simple if entrepreneurs are aware and equipped to preempt financial pitfalls:</p>
<h2><strong>Culture of frugality</strong></h2>
<p>From the get go, establish a culture that encourages thrift. While the startup is still finding its feet, spending happens faster than revenue is raked in. Therefore, it is in the company&#8217;s best interest to be as lean as possible in early investments. Reserve cash for &#8216;cold winters&#8217; such as pricing revisions, bad debts or slow sales. It is also a good idea for product companies to manage their inventories wisely. Too many products in stock can lead to unsold pieces and too little could mean lost sale opportunities.</p>
<p><em>What you can do</em>: Take a leaf out of the best practices of Decluttr Me, a startup that champions lean spending. Rather than outsourcing their artwork to exorbitantly priced designers, they took the DIY route with unconventional services such as <a href="https://www.fiverr.com/" target="_blank">Fiverr</a> and <a href="https://www.canva.com/" target="_blank">Canva</a>. Hire a lean team that is willing to roll up its sleeves and go beyond the call of duty, rather than unnecessarily overstaffing the company during its fledgling days. Resist the urge to splurge on frills such as expensive office furniture and decor when you have bigger financial commitments to take care of.</p>
<h2><strong>Invoice faster and better</strong></h2>
<p>Studies show that slow-paying customers are posing the biggest challenge to startups&#8217; cash flow. For a startup to flourish, it is essential to shorten billing cycles in order to cover for any delays in recovering costs incurred.</p>
<p><em>What you can do</em>: Sometimes, asking for a down payment before the commencement of a project can make entrepreneurs uneasy. But building an honest relationship with clients is the key to helping them understand the value you add to their businesses through the costs incurred in the process. When they do adhere to your policies, reciprocate their cooperation with a discount or incentive.</p>
<h2><strong>Let automation software do the heavy-lifting for you!</strong></h2>
<p>There is little place for nasty surprises in startups. Many a time, entrepreneurs set out believing their offering will take the market by storm. While some revel in the success of their ideas taking wings, the others are left to wonder where they went wrong. <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/06/iot-startup-fail/" target="_blank">Even if you have put in immeasurable effort in bringing your idea to life, there is always a chance that it may not make the cut</a>. Forecasting cash flows is predictive of such contingencies and helps to make suitable pivots to business strategy. It is also a credible method to build investor confidence in one&#8217;s business.</p>
<p><em>What you can do</em>: Disburse funds to employees across geographies for incidental expenses, track its use in real time and settle petty cash accounts with 100 percent accuracy. With the use of smartphones entrenched deeply in the way we do business, it is possible to predict, monitor and report cash flows with the click of a button. Imagine the potential of cash management without dealing with physical cash in the first place. With the adoption of automated solutions to manage petty cash, it can now become a reality.</p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>In summary, good cash management is king and speaks volumes about an entrepreneur&#8217;s understanding of his/her business. The benefits are evident for startups who have consciously welcomed technology into their folds, to do the job. Apart from balanced cash flow in the business, it frees resources from the mundane rigmarole, such that they can be allocated to more productive functions. Therefore, an automated approach to cash management is quickly emerging as an efficient way to tide over rough patches and to re-emerge profitable for years to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/cash-management-tips-startup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Startups are the future of Karnataka: an interview with Industries Minister RV Deshpande</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/karnataka-startups-rv-deshpande/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/karnataka-startups-rv-deshpande/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 07:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vishal Krishna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Invest Karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[R V Deshpande]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startups]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176768</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When you find the annals of industry in Karnataka there is one name that has been etched in stone. R V Deshpande has been the Industries Minister three times and is responsible for ushering in the Information Technology boom in India. Legend has it that out of the Rs 28,000-crore worth of investments that was [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you find the annals of industry in Karnataka there is one name that has been etched in stone. <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/11/r_v-deshpande-industry-minister-karnataka/" target="_blank">R V Deshpande</a> has been the Industries Minister three times and is responsible for ushering in the Information Technology boom in India. Legend has it that out of the Rs 28,000-crore worth of investments that was pitched in Karnataka, during his different tenures as Industries Minister, he was personally responsible for signing in Rs 18,000 crore. There is this saying in the Karnataka Udyog Mitra that he is the first to arrive in the office and the last to leave late in the evening. He also manages to do two social events a day and meet several businessmen. But, of late, his love has been to make Karnataka the startup capital of the country.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/InvestKarnataka-RV-Deshpande.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176772" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/InvestKarnataka-RV-Deshpande.jpg" alt="InvestKarnataka-RV-Deshpande" width="800" height="400" /></a></p>
<p>Here are the excerpts of an interview with the Heavy and Medium Industries Minister:</p>
<p><strong>Q: <em>With Invest Karnataka 2016 just around the corner what can we expect for startups?</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Minister</strong><strong>. </strong>Let me tell you that history has been on Karnataka’s side. Sixteen years ago, when we set up an investors meet in Bangalore, nobody realised how big Karnataka would become for the IT industry. Those investments that came in have now resulted in creating a system of talent and meritocracy. Today, several mid-level engineers, those who were freshers then, have become startup founders. The IT industry has gone global and Karnataka alone has close to half of the total IT exports of India. Coming to startups, we have a slew of announcements to help them. Everyone knows about the fund of funds that we are going to announce, and with them we have several schemes already running for bio-tech startups and semi-conductor startups. On February 3 and 4, startups should come and meet industry experts, government officials and talk about their needs. Let me be clear that Karnataka’s startups will have solutions for India, and we expect, with this new policy, that we will again be a pioneer in policy making.</p>
<p><strong>Q:</strong><em><strong> Do you expect any startup from manufacturing?  </strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Minister</strong><strong>:</strong><strong> </strong>Today, manufacturing by definition cannot be considered a startup. But if there is a technology linkage between markets, say, a startup that can enable price discovery from farms to manufacturing in the food processing industry, it’s a great business. Any new company which uses technology, connecting consumers and businesses, is a startup. But there are also product startups. Data collection and analytics is another startup business. Manufacturing is our thrust area; while the larger firms automate they will need ancillaries to make components. We are going to support the entry of many medium-sized manufacturers. Defence is a major thrust area for us.</p>
<p><strong>Q: <em>You seem to want to create a network of smaller cities becoming industrial towns. What are your plans?</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Minister: </strong>Yes, places like Kolar, Mysore, Hubli and Tumkur have already witnessed manufacturers moving there.  I am personally involved in making this a reality because jobs have to be created in all these areas.  Also, these regions have good colleges to cater to the industry. I am talking to several colleges to have entrepreneur cells. The government will support these entrepreneurs through their respective colleges.</p>
<p><strong>Q: <em>Karnataka is heavily dependent on hydel power. Do you see us increase our thermal capacities?</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>Minister: </strong>It’s currently a problem because we have witnessed two years of bad rainfall. It is, in fact, a drought-like situation. So I have again cleared coal-based power generation; we will generate 2,000 mega-watts by the middle of this year to help industry.</p>
<p><strong>Q: <em>What do you think of the competition from other States?</em></strong></p>
<p><strong> Minister. </strong>Let me be honest with you. A lot of our IT policies are foundations on which other States build upon. The more the competition the better for our country. I only believe that there are a lot of young ideas out there and need support. I would request all startups to come and witness what Invest Karnataka means to them.</p>
<p><em>YourStory is proud to partner with the Government of Karnataka’s ‘Invest Karnataka’ that will</em><em> </em><em>showcase the strides made in industrial development by the State and will also attract </em><em>investments</em><em> </em><em>from across the world. The <a href="http://investkarnataka2016.in/" target="_blank">event is to be held between 3 and 5 February 2016 in Bengaluru</a>(<strong><a href="http://investkarnataka2016.in" target="_blank">Register here</a></strong>).</em></p>
<figure id="attachment_176777" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Invest-Karnataka-app.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176777" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Invest-Karnataka-app.jpg" alt="Invest Karnataka app" width="800" height="402" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/ratna-prabha/" target="_blank">Ratna Prabha</a>(L) and <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/11/r_v-deshpande-industry-minister-karnataka/" target="_blank">R V Deshpande</a>(R) at the launch of Invest Karnataka App</figcaption></figure>
<p><em>With an aim to provide a digitally enhanced user platform to all the participants in the Invest Karnataka, Global Investors Summit, the Government of Karnataka recently launched the Invest Karnataka 2016 mobile application.<strong> You can <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.xvalue.invest_karnataka_2016&amp;hl=en" target="_blank">download the app on your Android device</a>.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/karnataka-startups-rv-deshpande/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcing YourStory Startup Sports League</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/yourstory-startup-sports-league/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/yourstory-startup-sports-league/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 05:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Team YS]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Play Arena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Sports League]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176541</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[India prides itself on being a sports crazy nation. We are crazy about watching sports that is. Be it cricket, tennis or football, we make very good cheerleaders. But how many of us actively play on the field? As torchbearers of the ‘disruptive generation’, it’s time, dear startups, to pull your punches and get ready [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India prides itself on being a sports crazy nation. We are crazy about watching sports that is. Be it cricket, tennis or football, we make very good cheerleaders. But how many of us actively play on the field?</p>
<p>As torchbearers of the ‘disruptive generation’, it’s time, dear startups, to pull your punches and get ready to kick some ball. Time to give the groaning bean bags respite, and the laptops some snooze time.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YSSL.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176548" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YSSL.jpg" alt="YSSL" width="800" height="400" /></a></p>
<p><strong>YourStory</strong> is bringing the <strong>Startup Sports League </strong>in association with<strong> <a href="https://playo.co/" target="_blank">Playo</a></strong>, one-of-a-kind event to help you exercise more than your brain cells. Time to give the groaning bean bags respite, and the laptops some snooze time as you pick up your sneakers instead. So go gather your team, do the Haka and show the ecosystem what your startup&#8217;s &#8216;team&#8217; spirit is really about. The sports league promises to level the playing field like never before; this is one place where it will not matter whether you are bootstrapped or you raised Series B!</p>
<p>A two day startup sports marathon for 1000+ participants  followed by a fun filled interactive Sports Night.</p>
<p><strong>Tournament:</strong><br />
Football matches will be played on artificial turf through the day and under lights on 5-a-side sized fields on Friday evening and Saturday. The Throwball tournament will 4-a-side format (mixed doubles with 2 women and men each per team) and played on a sand court (yeah..beach style) on Saturday</p>
<p><strong>Fun and Games:</strong><br />
Join in for exciting fun events conducted at the venue while waiting for your matches to keep your spirits high and hamstrings warm&#8230;no we don&#8217;t mean alcohol &#8211; not just yet atleast!! Be it wall climbing, paintball, laser tag, bowling, carting, fitness sessions, football experiential sessions, relays activities and physio sessions &#8211; feel free to take your pick from a host of activities.</p>
<p><strong>An finally. the Sports Night:</strong><br />
All yea gladiators, join us for the best sports-party ever!! Network your way through interactive panel sessions, fireside chats and the award ceremony while downing a few beers to toast your day&#8217;s on-field conquests. And as always, we save the best for the last &#8211; witness an epic Investors vs. Founders on-field futsal match &#8211; no red card rules applies on this one :).</p>
<p><strong>Startup Sports League Rules :</strong></p>
<p><strong>Football:</strong><br />
Matches will be played for in a League cum Knockout format. There need to be a maximum of 5 players per team on the field at any given time with upto 3 subs off-field. A team can make upto 5 substitutions per match during ball-outs. Each match will be 20 minutes long with 2 halves of 10 mins each.</p>
<p><strong>Throwball (Mixed Doubles):</strong><br />
Matches will be played for in a Knockout format. There need to be a maximum of 4 players per team on the court at any given time consisting of at least 2 women. Each match will be played to 21 points using the rally based scoring system.</p>
<p><strong>When : March 11th &amp; 12th, 2016</strong></p>
<p><strong>Where : Play Arena, Kasavanahalli, Bengaluru </strong>(<a href="https://www.google.co.in/maps/dir/''/playarina/data=!4m5!4m4!1m0!1m2!1m1!1s0x3bae136cd3c8209d:0xab9cb38fc4634cb3?sa=X&amp;ved=0ahUKEwin-Lmd6dDKAhXEQI4KHbNbCvsQ9RcIZjAL" target="_blank">Directions</a>)</p>
<p><a href="https://playo.co/ssl" target="_blank"><img class=" wp-image-115276 alignleft" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/register_button1.jpg" alt="register_button" width="216" height="46" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you have any further queries or interested in sponsoring or partnering for the event, Please contact <strong>ezhilan@yourstory.com / +91 9620090123</strong></p>
<div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/yourstory-startup-sports-league/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Story of a village boy from UP who made his way towards IIT BHU and built a Rs 28 crore entity</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/career-power/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/career-power/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 02:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aparajita Choudhury]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Accel Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banaras Hindu University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cognizant Technology Solutions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hyderabad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IBPS Clerk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indian Institute of Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indian Institute of Technology Joint Entrance Examination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indian Institutes of Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ITM University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jaypee Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kanpur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Khan Academy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online test preparation market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Tyaari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Global Management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176740</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Continuous brooding over fate will not offer you a platter of solutions. Learn to define your own destiny and tread path accordingly. Being raised in a farmer’s family in Dankaur, a small village in Uttar Pradesh, Anil Nagar since childhood believed in self-created destiny and decided to prepare for IIT JEE exam. Due to lack [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Continuous brooding over fate will not offer you a platter of solutions. Learn to define your own destiny and tread path accordingly. Being raised in a farmer’s family in Dankaur, a small village in Uttar Pradesh, Anil Nagar since childhood believed in self-created destiny and decided to prepare for <a href="http://yourstory.com/2014/11/gamification/" target="_blank">IIT JEE</a> exam. Due to lack of guidance on how to crack the exam he enrolled himself in a coaching centre. His hard work paid off and he cleared the exam in 1998 and pursued his BTech (electronics and communications) at <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/08/bridgedots/" target="_blank">IIT BHU</a>.</p>
<p>After having spent a long stint in the corporate world – working with <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/10/startup-rockstars-failure-lesson/" target="_blank">Jaypee Group</a>, <a href="http://yourstory.com/2013/07/noida-based-liqvid-helps-businesses-to-develop-online-learning-courses-plans-to-enter-consumer-space/" target="_blank">Liqvid</a> (Online education), <a href="http://yourstory.com/2014/09/suraj-saharan-delhivery/" target="_blank">ITM University</a>, and Cognizant Technology Solutions – Anil, Founder, quit his job in 2010 to start a testing preparation venture Career Power along with his friend Saurabh Bansal, Co-founder. The initial investment was Rs 1 lakh pooled in by the founders.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176743" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Saurabh-and-Anil.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176743" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Saurabh-and-Anil.jpg" alt="Saurabh Bansal and Anil Nagar" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Saurabh Bansal and Anil Nagar</figcaption></figure>
<p>Career Power is an organisation that is engaged in training students for government jobs and entrance exams in India. Today, the company boasts of with more than 70 <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/10/app-fridays-neuron-gym/" target="_blank">physical training</a> centres across India and claims to be the first company to launch online test preparations platform sscadda.com and bankersadda.com.</p>
<p>Anil, 37, says,</p>
<blockquote><p>bankersadda.com, a product of the same mother brand, is the most visited website by the aspirants with average daily hits crossing one million besides sscadda.com, which witnessed two million users last year.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Anil also pursued his <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/07/cheeky-chunk-pratik-doshi/" target="_blank">MBA</a> from <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/09/goa-startup-ecosystem/" target="_blank">Goa</a> Institute of Management. Saurabh, 32, is a finance graduate from college of Business Studies, <a href="http://yourstory.com/tag/delhi-university/" target="_blank">Delhi University</a>, and a master in finance from Delhi University. He gained 10 years of extensive experience working with KIPCO Group’s consulting arm, ICRA, and <a href="http://social.yourstory.com/2015/12/yes-bank-climate-change/" target="_blank">Yes Bank</a>.</p>
<h3><strong>A flashback</strong></h3>
<p>Career Power primarily started with classroom-based coaching centre, with its first branch in <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/10/yourstory-startup-spotlight-delhi/" target="_blank">Delhi</a>. Anil recalls that 26 out of 32 students in the first batch were selected for various jobs. Lack of funding posed a huge challenge for them when it came to expand the business, which decelerated the pace of initial growth. However, it helped them gain better control over both growth and value of money.</p>
<p>Saurabh avers,</p>
<blockquote><p>Our focussed approach and rigorous programmes help students in giving their best performance in these competitive exams. Regular assignments, tests, quizzes keep our students on the toes throughout their exam preparation.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Career Power currently has more than 700 employees, out of which more than 300 are teachers.</p>
<p><strong>Courses </strong></p>
<p>Career Power caters to two main exams – <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/05/toppr-funding-65_cr/" target="_blank">Bank Exams</a> and <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/onlinetyari/" target="_blank">SSC Exams</a>. With its online tests series for banks and SSC exams, students can self-assess their preparation along with their detailed analysis. The content team, which comprises subject matter experts, translators, and typists, always work on updating content as per the changing patterns of exams, preparing books, mock tests, and assignments.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176744" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Career-Power-Team.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176744" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Career-Power-Team.jpg" alt="Career Power Team" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Career Power Team</figcaption></figure>
<p>Bankersadda.com offers study materials on quantitative aptitude, reasoning aptitude, English language, daily words list (vocabulary), computer, marketing, banking and static GK. SSCAdda.com offers quantitative aptitude, English language, general studies, general intelligence, and railway notes. Career Power charges Rs 10,000 for regular classroom courses.</p>
<p>In the next two to three years, Career Power plans to strengthen the product offerings with CTET (Central Teacher Eligibility Test), Railways, NDA (National Defence Academy), and CDS.</p>
<p>Anil says,</p>
<blockquote><p>Generally, profit margins for offline classroom coaching are in the range of 25–26 per cent, while online business gives margins in excess of 50 per cent.”</p></blockquote>
<h3><strong>Gaining numbers</strong></h3>
<p>Career Power has trained approximately 28,000 students in FY 2015, out of which 16,000 students are from classroom programme and 12,000 students from online programme. It aims to train more than 1 lakh students by FY 2016 (50,000 students in classroom programme and 50,000 students in online programme).</p>
<p>In recently concluded exams, about 1,200 candidates got selected in <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/07/pyoopel-com/" target="_blank">IBPS</a> PO and IBPS Clerk (recruitment process of 2014–15) and more than 1,000 students have been selected in <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/sbi-snapdeal-e-commerce-loan/" target="_blank">SBI</a> PO (Pre) 2015. The startup plans to add 30 more branches and train more than 60,000 students in classroom programmes.</p>
<p>Currently, the branches of Career Power are spread across Delhi, Lucknow, Kanpur, Patna, Ranchi, Kolkata, Bhopal, Ahmedabad, Hyderabad and more. The startup plans to focus more on South India and Western India and open 30 more branches in Bengaluru, Chennai, Pune, Mumbai, Nagpur, Truchi, Vizag and more by 2016.</p>
<h3><strong>YourStory take</strong></h3>
<p>Over the last couple of years, online test preparation market has become a promising sector for startups to embark in backed by the growing usage of smartphone and significant traction of students. Even big coaching institutes like Career Launcher and <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/first-time-entrepreneur-problems/" target="_blank">TIME</a> have turned online with the test preparation modules. Moreover, the likes of Coursera, Udemy, Udacity, Khan Academy have broken the conventional mode of learning. <a href="http://yourstory.com/2014/05/toppr-funding/" target="_blank">Toppr</a>, <a href="http://yourstory.com/2014/06/online-education/" target="_blank">Embibe</a>, Online Tyaari, EntrancePrime, Cracku, and CrunchPrep GRE are few of the startup.</p>
<p>The online test prep industry is valued at $8 billion in India and over $80 billion globally. Moreover, this space has witnessed a spate of investor activity with top venture capital firms validating their growth potential. Bengaluru-based <a href="http://yourstory.com/2014/01/vedantu/" target="_blank">Vedantu</a> raised $5 million from <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/03/accel-partners-india-iv-fund-startups/" target="_blank">Accel Partners</a> and Tiger Global Management, <a href="http://yourstory.com/2014/05/toppr-funding/" target="_blank">Toppr</a> raised Rs 65 crore for expansion in May, <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/09/onlinetyari-funding/" target="_blank">OnlineTyaari </a>raised Rs 5 crore from both angel and VC investors.</p>
<p>However, Delhi-based Career Power appeared to avoid taking the most feasible route of funding. Moreover, with more than 70 physical training centres, it is growing parallel in both online and offline. The company has maintained a steady growth by being bootstrapped for the last five years. It has witnessed revenue of Rs. 28 crore in FY 2014–15 and for FY 2015–16, it is expecting a revenue of Rs 30 crore.</p>
<p>Anil says “We have grown by 200 per cent over last year in terms of our offline business, while growth in online is expected to be approx 500 per cent.”</p>
<p>In terms of product offerings, the startup will soon offer videos, live classes, online doubt clearing, online interactive books and more through web and mobile applications.</p>
<p><a href="http://careerpower.in/" target="_blank">Career Power</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/career-power/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Starting up in uncharted territories – The North Karnataka story</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/invest-karnataka-begaum-hubli-dharwad/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/invest-karnataka-begaum-hubli-dharwad/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 02:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Prateeksha Nayak]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Invest Karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amit Doshi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anand G. Naik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basic infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business incubators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronic product startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government of Karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kooki Consumer Electronics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Karnataka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santosh Huralikoppi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology hub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vivek Pawar]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176748</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[YourStory is proud to partner with the Government of Karnataka’s ‘Invest Karnataka’ that will showcase the strides made in industrial development by the State and will also attract investments from across the world. The event is to be held between 3 and 5 February 2016 in Bengaluru. As we begin the countdown to the event, we shine a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em>YourStory is proud to partner with the Government of Karnataka’s ‘<a href="http://yourstory.com/invest-karnataka/" target="_blank">Invest Karnataka</a>’ that will</em><em> </em><em>showcase the strides made in industrial development by the State and will also attract </em><em>investments</em><em> </em><em>from across the world. The <a href="http://investkarnataka2016.in/" target="_blank">event is to be held between 3 and 5 February 2016 in Bengaluru</a>. As we begin the countdown to the event, we shine a spotlight on North Karnataka that is quickly emerging as a technology hub.</em></p></blockquote>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176749" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/InvestKarnataka.jpg" alt="InvestKarnataka" width="800" height="400" /></p>
<p>Rustic charm, multi-lingual culture, and a cosmopolitan outlook, North Karnataka with its largely untapped market is waiting to be explored! This commercial hub is home to a wide cluster of industries and has more than one lakh small and medium industries and the number is just growing. The region is now witnessing a revolutionary crop of entrepreneurs who are taking these very traditional businesses to a whole new level with a technological twist. In this story, we trace the beginning of an ecosystem in a territory where access to something as basic as a telephone connection and electricity was once a challenge and uttering the dreaded ‘Technology’ word, an act of bravery.</p>
<h2><strong>The initial struggle</strong></h2>
<p><strong>“We had to scramble for a landline connection. We were among the first few to have access to telephonic communication in the region, when we started operations,”</strong> says Santosh Huralikoppi, CEO, NSI. Challenges for entrepreneurs who went against the tide to startup were aplenty. In a land dominated by agriculture and commercial trade, entrepreneurs who wanted to dabble in technology felt like outcastes. However, lack of players in the market proved to be a bitter-sweet experience for ones taking the unconventional route back then. While the market was largely untouched, not many were willing to take the digital route to go to the next level. Convincing traditional businessmen to invest in something intangible was quite an uphill task. But things started changing slowly for the better.</p>
<h2><strong>Building a network</strong></h2>
<p>So how did they manage to get out of a situation so dissuading? They joined hands! “That has always been the case, even today we thrive on the business we give to each other,” says Shashank Revankar Founder, Kooki Consumer Electronics, an electronic product startup based out of Hubli. Unlike bigger cities where cut-throat competition and blame-games are a norm, the startup ecosystem in this region is flourishing because of old school values like unity and friendship. Speaking of building, how difficult is it to build and retain a team in a city where most techies would not prefer to live in, owing to limited job opportunities and lack of infrastructure? “We need good managers to retain employees and keep the team motivated,” says Vivek Pawar, Executive CEO of Sankalp Semiconductors, a company which began operations in the year 2005 with 10 employees and is one the fastest growing analog andmixed-signal semiconductor companies in India with 450 employees, which began operations in Hubli.</p>
<h2><strong>External support</strong></h2>
<p>While being there for each other is of great help, support from the government is largely lacking. Stating that there not many policies in place and stressing on the policy of self-help is the best help, Santosh says,<strong>“In regions like these, you need to fend for yourselves. Startups in general need to survive on their own.”</strong>But why are investors shying away from investing in startups in the region? <strong>“Big giants will come to Hubli when there are many entrepreneurs with great ideas. The number has to grow,”</strong> reasons Vivek. “Events like <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/10/techsparks-city-meetups-2015-startup-tips/" target="_blank">TechSparks that came to Hubli in 2015</a> were extremely helpful and it is events like these that will open new doors for entrepreneurs in the region,” says Anand G. Naik, MD and CEO, Boredbees Tech Solutions Pvt Ltd, stressing on the difference media intervention can make.</p>
<h2><strong>What it looks like today</strong></h2>
<p>Cut to today, the startup ecosystem in North Karnataka looks as vibrant and promising as in any big city. What is most striking is how ideas have popped out of features distinct to the region.<strong>“We struck upon an idea to startup after a distress call from a Mercedes owner stuck in the wild Western Ghats with multiple flat tyres,” </strong>says Amit Doshi, Co-founder, Fit my tyre, an on-demand tyre replacement company operating out of Belgaum. Conventional businesses are now realising the revolutionary powers of technology and are embracing it more than ever which is encouraging a larger sect of the population to take the entrepreneurial plunge.</p>
<h2><strong>The road ahead</strong></h2>
<p>With territories marked and basic infrastructure in place, the journey of the startup ecosystem in North Karnataka has only begun. Belgaum being listed among the top 20 smart cities by the Government is also an interesting development to note. Given the size of the market and a large number of prestigious technological universities, things are looking bright and promising. But what would be the ‘one thing’ that could set startups from this part of the country apart from the rest?</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>“Startup with a purpose that is beyond money, startup to make for India,”</strong> says Vivek.</p></blockquote>
<p>Wise leaders, great ideas and a largely untapped market, North Karnataka is definitely going to be a space to watch out for!</p>
<p><em>With an aim to provide a digitally enhanced user platform to all the participants in the Invest Karnataka, Global Investors Summit, the Government of Karnataka recently launched the Invest Karnataka 2016 mobile application.<strong> You can <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.xvalue.invest_karnataka_2016&amp;hl=en" target="_blank">download the app on your Android device</a>.</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/invest-karnataka-begaum-hubli-dharwad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>This US-returned techie aims to make Indian schools data-driven and transparent with SchoolCom</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/schoolcom/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/schoolcom/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 01:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sindhu Kashyap]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EduTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet connection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offline-online syncing technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology_Internet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176727</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Remember Monday mornings when you were in school? Beginning the day groggily and annoyingly early. The hustle into morning assembly, the attendance, and the homework. So imagine its 9 am on a Monday and the class teacher of Class VI takes attendance on a tab. All he or she has to do is pull out a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Remember Monday mornings when you were in school? Beginning the day groggily and annoyingly early. The hustle into morning assembly, the attendance, and the homework. So imagine its 9 am on a Monday and the class teacher of Class VI takes attendance on a tab. All he or she has to do is pull out a tab and mark absentees. An SMS is triggered to the parents of all the absentees almost instantaneously.</p>
<p>All this happens in a school situated in one of the remotest towns of India where a reliable Internet connection is almost impossible. This is what SchoolCom does. It helps simplify decision making in schools by making data capturing and analysis sharp and efficient.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176729" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YourStory-SchoolCom.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176729" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YourStory-SchoolCom.jpg" alt="YourStory-SchoolCom" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Core team @ SchoolCom</figcaption></figure>
<h2><strong>Building an intuitive data capturing product</strong></h2>
<p>SchoolCom has built a platform “SmartTab” that is a focussed device pre-fed with master data of a particular school like student records, modules, teachers, sections, and other details. The product has inbuilt Wi-Fi connectivity and offline-online syncing technology.</p>
<p>It has intuitive and customisable data capture modules so the teacher can record any kind of data the way he or she wants. All of this data is then transformed into simple graphics to help the teacher make sense and analyse the data captured. The tablets can also record the data offline and can also be easily synced over a regular 2G network.</p>
<p>The tablets also help measure a student’s performance on a day-to-day basis. There is also an in-built messaging system that allows teachers to update the student’s parents with their child’s performance and day-to-day activities.</p>
<h2><strong>Working with schools</strong></h2>
<p>The idea of SchoolCom came to Mangalram Purushotam while he was in the US. After completing his masters from Georgia Institute of Technology, Mangal was working as a consultant for a technology company.</p>
<p>“I came back from the US to manage Indian schools and realised that data capturing is a very big issue that most schools face,” says 31-year-old Mangal. He adds that for the principal it was almost impossible to make important day-to-day decisions in a short span of time. “It was then I decided to develop a product that could make a teacher’s life much simpler and be strongly data driven.”</p>
<p>Saurabh Saxena, a friend who also had years of experience in software development and has been ranked among the top 500 programmers in the world, joined in as the Co-founder. Starting with a team of four, with Saurabh as the lead developer, the team built the first MVP of SchoolCom in early 2013.</p>
<h2><strong>Traction and growth</strong></h2>
<p>In the initial days, the team worked hard to understand the requirements of the teachers and students. So they would spend the time in schools understanding how they functioned, and soon they onboarded 3,000 students in 2013; that number has now grown to 100,000 students.</p>
<p>The team claims that they are growing at 100 per cent every year, thus making it easier to meet their expenses and grow at the same time. The team gets its revenues through the sale of its product – SmartTab, which varies for every school basis their requirements. SchoolCom has declined sharing its revenue figures.</p>
<h2><strong>Future plans</strong></h2>
<p>“We want to have a million kids on the platform by 2017. We have already gone past 10 per cent of it with no external funding,” adds Mangal.</p>
<p>The team is now working on a new platform called Flap. They are working with leading teachers and subject matter experts from across the world to create repositories and study material regarding various courses and subjects right from mathematics to music. Mangal says this will allow single or community-based users to just login to the platform from any of their devices and redefine their learning experience.</p>
<h2><strong>YourStory take</strong></h2>
<p>With the increased focus on our education system, and with the different government policies that are pushing towards literary initiatives, data capturing for schools becomes essential. SchoolCom replicates the model of its UK counterpart SchoolComm.</p>
<p>A survey stated that close to 23 crore children are studying in close to 13 lakh schools across India. In 2013, there was a 13.67 per cent growth in student enrollements from Classes 1- 12. According to an IBEF report, the Indian higher education system is one the largest in the world with over 70 million students enrolling in less than 20 years.</p>
<p>While the numbers look promising, one of the biggest challenges most Indian schools face is the lack of the right infrastructure. In several schools in rural areas, there is said to be a lack of even proper drinking water facilities. Many even lack the basic supplies like stationery, so while the plan for schoolrooms using tabs for multiple schools across India is great, using it in rural areas might be a challenge.</p>
<p><a href="http://schoolcom.in/" target="_blank">Website </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/schoolcom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Baba Ramdev’s Patanjali takes the hyperlocal way</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/pluss-patanjali/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/pluss-patanjali/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 13:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Team YS]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atit Jain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baba Ramdev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hyperlocal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Madhulika Pandey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Delhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online company features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pluss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tarun Lawadia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176715</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sooner than later, Baba Ramdev’s Patanjali has chosen to go hyperlocal. Gurgaon-based startup for hyperlocal delivery of medicines and healthcare products, Pluss will be delivering Patanjali products. With the revenues of over 2500 crore, Patanjali is currently one of the top five FMCG companies in India. Its products, including nutrition, hair care, skin care, dental care and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sooner than later, Baba Ramdev’s Patanjali has chosen to go <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/08/hyperlocal-e_commerce/" target="_blank">hyperlocal</a>. Gurgaon-based startup for hyperlocal delivery of medicines and healthcare products, Pluss will be delivering Patanjali products. With the revenues of over 2500 crore, Patanjali is currently one of the top five FMCG companies in India. Its products, including nutrition, hair care, skin care, dental care and toiletries, will be sold through the Pluss App across the national capital. The FMCG major already sells its products online via <a href="http://patanjaliayurved.net/" target="_blank">web portal</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Patanjali-hyperlocal.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176728" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Patanjali-hyperlocal.jpg" alt="Patanjali-hyperlocal" width="800" height="400" /></a></p>
<p>Commenting on this tie-up, Madhulika Pandey, the Co-founder of Pluss said,</p>
<blockquote><p>Patanjali brand has already secured a position in the list of top five FMCG companies of India with an enormous consumer base and therefore, we as an on-demand platform that addresses the consumers’ urgent pharmaceutical and health needs, decided to bring them on board.</p></blockquote>
<p>Pluss was ncorporated in 2015 by Atit Jain, Madhulika Pandey and Tarun Lawadia after witnessing the country&#8217;s largely unorganized health care industry, which otherwise is worth billions of dollars. In a country where everything, including groceries and food, is delivered at the doorstep in a day, the problem of timely medicine delivery remains unsolved. Through their own fleet of delivery executives, named as ‘Pluss Men’, Pluss takes the responsibility of fulfilling the orders on time.</p>
<p>The company has <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/11/pluss-funding/" target="_blank">raised $1 million pre-Series A funding</a> from IDG Ventures India, m &amp; s partners (Singapore) and Powerhouse Ventures (USA). Pluss operates in Delhi and Gurgaon and claims to do close to 15,000 orders on a monthly basis(as of November 2015).</p>
<p>The health products market is expected to grow at a CAGR of 15 percent and touch $158.2 billion in 2017. Experts believe that solving medicine procurement problem is a sizeable opportunity</p>
<p>Pluss features four main product categories – Baby Care, Pet care, Personal Wellness and Daily Essentials, which are further, divided into subcategories and have hundreds of products in total. The on-demand medicine delivery app standardizes user experience irrespective of the location and the store from where medicines are delivered. The app is available both on android and iOS.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/pluss-patanjali/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The SEU-IN network intends to connect the Indian and European startup ecosystems</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/seu-in-network/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/seu-in-network/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 13:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Team YS]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aarin Capital Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ambassador]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ambassadors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amsterdam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[calibre network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crosspring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital giants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[European Union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luigi Mercuri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mauro Romaldini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netherlands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Siemens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stockholm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Supercell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T.V. Mohandas Pai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tomasz Kozlowski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Waste management]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176732</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When India talks about its startup ecosystem, Silicon Valley invariably figures in the conversation. Not São Paolo, not Singapore, not Stockholm, and not any other startup ecosystem that’s making great strides. Maybe it’s because we simply do not know them, or what they do. These are the gaps the Startup Europe India Network (SEU-IN), launched [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When India talks about its startup ecosystem, Silicon Valley invariably figures in the conversation. Not São Paolo, not Singapore, not Stockholm, and not any other startup ecosystem that’s making great strides. Maybe it’s because we simply do not know them, or what they do. These are the gaps the <strong>Startup Europe India Network (SEU-IN)</strong>, launched on 28 January, intends to bridge.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176733" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Connecting-India_Europe_Cover_Yourstory.jpg" alt="Connecting-India_Europe_Cover_Yourstory" width="800" height="400" /></p>
<p>The high-calibre network, led by Praveen Paranjothi and Mauro Romaldini, has set out to bring together key stakeholders in the Indian and European startup ecosystems to increase interaction and open up more growth and funding. The network’s founding collaborators include the European Commission’s Startup Europe initiative, Cambridge University’s Centre for India and Global Business, Holland Fintech, and Crosspring, Netherlands, giving it a solid foundation to build upon and rapidly expand.</p>
<h2><strong>Why Europe? Why now?</strong></h2>
<p>For every Skype, Spotify, Rovio (Angry Birds) and Supercell (Clash of Clans) that made it big, there are multiple European startups that Indians are unaware of. And for every Flipkart and InMobi that Europe knows of, there are other Indian players nobody’s talking about. India knows corporate Europe well – the likes of Siemens, SAP, Vodafone, Nokia, and Bosch have been in the country for decades, so connections and familiarity run deep.</p>
<p>Paranjothi, a Europe-based Indian venture capitalist with years of corporate, investment, and startup experience across Europe and the US, is well-placed to drive this. Along with Romaldini, a seasoned international finance professional who as Founding VP has been working on the initiative for the past four months, Paranjothi wants to create more opportunities for startups and investors in both locations to collaborate, build strategic partnerships, and create value.</p>
<p>Together, they’ve roped in high-powered advisers like T.V. Mohandas Pai, Chairman of Aarin Capital Partners; Tomasz Kozlowski, the EU ambassador to India, Uli Grabenwarter, Deputy Director of the European Investment Fund (the largest VC investor on the continent), and Isidro Laso Ballesteros, head of the European Commission’s Startup Europe Sector.</p>
<p>In turn, this core set of advisors will expand SEU-IN by identifying and appointing ‘ambassadors’ in various areas (industry, research, academia, and investment), who will serve as local points-of-contact in startup hubs across India and Europe (Berlin, Amsterdam, Stockholm, Paris, and London).</p>
<h2><strong>Tapping into untapped opportunities</strong></h2>
<p>To start with, the network is looking connect the two very vibrant ecosystems by offering partnerships, memberships, sponsorships, and other potential engagement avenues to startups. Much has been said about India’s market size and potential, especially as tech-based startups emerge and thrive. &#8220;Uniting startups in two global regions means more customers, more investments, and more growth. The initiative’s ambition is exponential. Unlocking the potential of the fastest-growing tech businesses on both sides of the world would mean more opportunities for every one of us,&#8221; Ballesteros remarked.</p>
<p>Luigi Mercuri of the Italian Trade Agency and SEU-IN Ambassador, Germany, described how the network would foster interaction through multiple channels of communication supported by reliable local experts: &#8220;SEU-IN represents an agile, tailor-made vessel to safely navigate between two of globalisation&#8217;s rising digital giants.&#8221;</p>
<h2><strong>What’s on the agenda?</strong></h2>
<p>As a first step, SEU-IN has a specific focus on 10 areas: Fintech, Cyber Security, Intelligence (data, machine and artificial), Smart Cities, Edtech, Agritech, Healthtech, Automotive Tech, Waste Management, and Business and Government Tech. Within these sectors, it will engage with startups and scaleups (growth companies), as well as investors, corporates, incubators, accelerators, innovators, universities, and the government. <strong>The goal, according to Paranjothi, is to increase collaboration, growth and investments within and between the two ecosystems, with SEU-IN as a channel for seamless engagement. </strong></p>
<p>Tomasz Kozlowski says, “SEU-IN, with its ambitious mission to bring together key players and experts (startups, investors, corporate, and public initiatives) from Europe and India to create and leverage opportunities between the thriving digital markets, will play an important role.”</p>
<p>Pai described SEU-IN as an initiative that would bring together “an extraordinary group of innovators with the ability to influence global trends”. At <strong>YourStory</strong>, that’s exactly the type of change we love to drive and be a part of. Here’s to new discoveries and new relationships!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.startupeuropeindia.net" target="_blank">The SEU-IN website</a></p>
<p>(Disclaimer: T.V. Mohandas Pai is an investor in YourStory.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/seu-in-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How ShopClues joined the Unicorn club</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/shopclues/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/shopclues/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 12:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Athira A Nair]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[In Depth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arvind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arvind Singhal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DHgate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e - commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E-commerce in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gurgaon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[helion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indias Unicorn club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radhika Aggarwal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rakuten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sanjay Sethi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ShopClues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silicon Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapdeal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technopak]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176690</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few months ago, Sanjay Sethi and Radhika Aggarwal were walking out of Delhi airport when they saw a family waiting for someone, with gifts in ShopClues boxes. “Radhika and I were so excited that we took a selfie with them,” says Sanjay, Co-founder of the newest e-commerce entrant to India’s Unicorn club. The country’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago, Sanjay Sethi and Radhika Aggarwal were walking out of Delhi airport when they saw a family waiting for someone, with gifts in ShopClues boxes. “Radhika and I were so excited that we took a selfie with them,” says Sanjay, Co-founder of the newest e-commerce entrant to India’s Unicorn club.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Shopclues_Infographic3-02.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176708" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Shopclues_Infographic3-02.png" alt="Shopclues_Infographic3-02" width="801" height="401" /></a></p>
<p>The country’s first managed marketplace, founded in July 2011 in Silicon Valley by Radhika’s husband Sandeep Aggarwal, ShopClues is run by co-founders Sanjay Sethi and Radhika Aggarwal. ShopClues was the 36<sup>th</sup> entrant in India’s e-commerce market, when they started operations here in 2012, headquartered in Gurgaon. Becoming a <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/shopclues-funding-unicorn/" target="_blank">billion-dollar company </a>in less than four years was exciting. But as far as Sanjay is concerned, these are just numbers. “We have miles to go before we sleep. What we get today is the fruit of our efforts &#8211; what we do today will give us our future,” he says.</p>
<h2>More growth in pipeline</h2>
<p>Having raised $100million in their latest round, Series E, of funding led by Singapore-based GIC, ShopClues will focus on profitability for the next 18 months. While aiming to be the first e-commerce company of any size to become profitable, they are hoping to grow their current strategies rather than begin new ones.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176693" style="width: 160px;" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Sanjay-Sethi-CEO-Co-Founder-ShopClues.jpg"><img class="wp-image-176693 size-full" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Sanjay-Sethi-CEO-Co-Founder-ShopClues.jpg" alt="Sanjay Sethi, CEO &amp; Co-Founder, ShopClues" width="160" height="160" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Sanjay Sethi, CEO, ShopClues</figcaption></figure>
<p>“We have demonstrated in the past that growth and profitability are not mutually exclusive. We have been and will continue to be capital efficient, independent of the money we have raised,” says Sanjay. He adds that though other players have had 20 times more money, ShopClues grew rapidly by focusing on lower price points. “Categories and consumers in the upper income group don’t matter; we want those who are looking for a wider selection, and lower price points,” he says.</p>
<h2>More Acquisitions?</h2>
<p>Although ShopClues invested in hyperlocal services marketplace HeyBiz towards end -2015, there is currently limited funds for large cash deals. “But as in the past, we will continue to deploy money in some sectors and acquire or acqui-hire in two or three areas in M&amp;A: mostly payments, data analytics, and mobility,” says Sanjay.</p>
<p>Sanjay adds that while <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/commerce-logistics-2016/" target="_blank">logistics </a>is crucial, ShopClues has no plans to enter the fray. “We have 40 logistics partners at the regional, local and national level. Delhivery, Ecom Express are all doing a very good job, so they can continue to do so,” he added.</p>
<p>However, there is some scepticism among experts. Arvind Singhal, Chairman of advisory firm Techno Pak, believes that investment in logistics and distribution centres is essential in the future. “Third- or fourth-party logistics partners are not the way forward for major players. For the likes of <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/10/shimply/" target="_blank">Craftsvilla</a> or Jaypore, with small revenues, there is no point investing in delivery and storage. But for a pan-India marketplace serving a wider market, control over your delivery capabilities is essential,” he says.</p>
<p>Currently, most customers are comfortable with delivery in 4-5 days. But Arvind says that when more players start offering <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/instant-delivery/" target="_blank">same day delivery </a>(only Amazon does now), others will have to follow suit.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Shopclues_Infographic3-01.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176710" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Shopclues_Infographic3-01.png" alt="Shopclues_Infographic3-01" width="800" height="1183" /></a></p>
<h2>Expansion plans</h2>
<p>Since ShopClues follows lower price points, expansion plans are based on it too. “We may not provide an iPhone or Samsung, but for a smartphone at Rs 4,000-8,000 like Lava or <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/11/micromax-ecosystem-startups/" target="_blank">Micromax</a>, we are the go-to place. We will now focus on refurbished electronics as well as fashion and furniture at lower price points for lower demographics,” Sanjay said.</p>
<p>But Arvind says that <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/flipkart-global/" target="_blank">Flipkart </a>and <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/freecharge-go/" target="_blank">Snapdeal </a>also offer various price points. They all offer discounts as they are better funded. By focusing on lower price points, ShopClues might get a larger volume of transactions. Yet, cost of operations is high, and unless transaction values are higher, there will be no profit. Sanjay agrees that he would make profit if he charges for shipping. “But nobody else is doing it; so we have to follow suit,” he says.</p>
<p>ShopClues investor Sanjeev Aggarwal, Co-founder &#8211; Senior Managing Director, Helion, believes that Flipkart and <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/12/snapdeal-2015-story/" target="_blank">Snapdeal </a>serve a different section and hence have a unique positioning.  Most Unicorns are solving problems of urban India while ShopClues is solving the problems of real India, he says. “ShopClues has developed a marketplace for the masses by building a technology platform that connects Tier II and Tier III customers to regional/local brands. This in turn has led to best-in-class metrics on unit economics and capital efficiency,” he adds.</p>
<p>Will ShopClues benefit from focusing on lower income groups and smaller cities? Arvind says it is possible if they provide curated selections. “Flipkart’s revenue is 15 times that of ShopClues; all the players serve smaller cities and give lower opening price points. We don’t need another marketplace but a well-curated one –such as CraftsVilla or <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/12/pretty-laces-wine-cheese-opening-zivames-first-fitting-lounge-bengaluru/" target="_blank">Zivame</a>.”</p>
<h2><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Shopclues_Infographic3-03.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176711" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Shopclues_Infographic3-03.png" alt="Shopclues_Infographic3-03" width="801" height="201" /></a></h2>
<h2>Plans for 2016</h2>
<p>ShopClues is not planning any drastic change with the new funds. So, 25 per cent of investment will be in product and technology; 25 per cent in acquisitions, mergers and partnerships; and 50 per cent in marketing and brand building.</p>
<p>ShopClues has tie ups with merchants in China and Korea to provide a wider selection and value for consumers. “We have partnered with DHgate &#8211; China’s second-largest wholesale player &#8211; 10,000 merchants in China are now selling to India. But Indian e-commerce is still only less than 2 per cent of total retail; so 98 per cent of retail market is yet to be captured,” Sanjay added.</p>
<p>Sanjay says that every city has a different market, so no single player can dominate. He says: “No one player can cater to all consumers. We targets households with incomes between Rs 4-10 lakh.”</p>
<h2>Way forward</h2>
<p><a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/indian-ecommerces-best-kept-secret/" target="_blank">E-Commerce in India </a>is flooded with funding, but not making a profit yet. “There is no reason to make money now. But, if we are to do business on our own money, we will weed out categories that are not making profit,” says Sanjay.</p>
<p>E-commerce is only five years old in India. We are still a long way from an eBay, which makes $5 million or Japan’s Rakuten which makes $2 billion, annually. Sanjeev says that the focus is back on employee satisfaction, world-class technology, delivering great customer experience and ensuring that unit economics are in place. It is yet to be seen if Unicorns, after all, can exist off-paper and find profit and sustainability in the real world.</p>
<h2>[Now watch] In 90 seconds: Know about India&#8217;s latest entrant in the Unicorn Club</h2>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b2Dgu7vvQxI" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Graphics by Gokul K</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/shopclues/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 reasons why art and humanities graduates need to start up</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/art-humanities-students-startup/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/art-humanities-students-startup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 11:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guest Author]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Ideas/Plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[great entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humanities graduates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rahul Maurya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rajdhani College]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology- pros]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[www.dustack.com]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176561</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is energy and thrill in the air for the new generation of entrepreneurs and students having a passion for technology and an enthusiasm for innovation. When you see news flashing of the recent launch of #startupindia, you may question what it has to do with you. Let me tell you why, even though you [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is energy and thrill in the air for the new generation of entrepreneurs and students having a passion for technology and an enthusiasm for innovation.</p>
<p>When you see news flashing of the recent launch of #startupindia, you may question what it has to do with you. Let me tell you why, even though you are still art or humanities graduate student, you may want to start taking advantage of the positive climate in the startup ecosystem straightaway.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/advertisement_startups.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-168278" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/advertisement_startups.jpg" alt="advertisement_startups" width="800" height="400" /></a></p>
<h2><strong>1) Non-engineers have been tagged as a less creative breed of students.</strong></h2>
<p>We have to admit the fact that this tag persists strongly in the minds of a lot of technology- pros who have passed out of premier tech or management institutions likes of IITs and IIMs. Often, B.Sc/B.Com/B.A. students are reviewed lesser over their capability in tech and startup events. So it’s now a question of displaying our self-belief and show our potential.</p>
<h2><strong>2) We are more social animals than engineers:</strong></h2>
<p>We are more social and well versed in ground realities, grassroot problems and micro-detailing of daily life functioning, because we spent less time on books and classes and more time outside. We can protest about anything we feel strongly against, with confidence, arrange a large gathering in no time, interact and make connections anywhere, and have the ability of working in not just a small team but in large groups, which is something all entrepreneurs should know how to do. We just need to work on our technical side and collaborative learning.</p>
<h2><strong>3) We will not be placed easily</strong></h2>
<p>Now is a good time to accept the bitter fact that graduation colleges don’t get those astronomical number of recruiters promising quality jobs. It’s not that they don’t get placed but a large chunk of students either gets into call-centre jobs or something of lesser value, with light paychecks. So what about our dreams of having a reunion in San Francisco? Should we let go of them? Absolutely not. If we have to shape our future by our own hands we need to put some extra effort and get out of our comfort zone to think like an entrepreneur and find solutions for ground-zero problems, in which we are more experienced than others. For us, entrepreneurship isn’t an option but necessity. There are so many examples of entrepreneurs who have not passed out with fancy IIT degrees, but doing phenomenal work and spearheading innovations.</p>
<p>Taking into account our experience, capabilities and needs we must go after entrepreneurship and create solutions for ground issues. We must generate more opportunities and set an example for those hesitating to go forward that it’s not instruments or money but the robust foundation of any idea that makes a great entrepreneur.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Rahul-Maurya.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-176572" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Rahul-Maurya.jpg" alt="Rahul-Maurya" width="120" height="148" /></a>About the Author:</strong></p>
<p>Rahul Maurya is a IInd year student of Rajdhani College, DU pursuing BSc Computer Science. He is a core science lover and avid book worm. He&#8217;s evangelizing entrepreneurship in his college by initiating group discussions within colleges. He&#8217;s currently working on an online ed-stack <a href="http://www.dustack.com/" target="_blank">www.dustack.com</a>. You can follow him on Twitter @Rahul_Science</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>(Disclaimer: The views and opinions expressed in this article are those of the author and do not necessarily reflect the views of YourStory.)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/art-humanities-students-startup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>TiE Bangalore showcase: meet 7 startups riding the fin-tech wave</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/tie-bangalore-showcase-startups-fin-tech/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/tie-bangalore-showcase-startups-fin-tech/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 07:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Madanmohan Rao]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abdul Hadi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aisces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anuj Pachoree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benson Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bhargavi Sridharan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CoinSecure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ernst & Young]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial advisors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FinMitra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FxKart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hari Haran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jincy Samuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[K.S. Ravi Shankar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[merchant devices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mohit Kalra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MyMoneySage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OnUs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TiE Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel reimbursement claims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XPense Manager]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176651</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When will bitcoin take off in India? Will Indian consumers entrust their wealth to financial advisors on marketplace sites? Is there a big enough market for a mobile tool to help manage business expenses? For two hours, seven entrepreneurs pitched their ideas and offerings to an expert jury at TiE Bangalore’s first startup showcase of [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When will bitcoin take off in India? Will Indian consumers entrust their wealth to financial advisors on marketplace sites? Is there a big enough market for a mobile tool to help manage business expenses?</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176680" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Founders.jpg" alt="Founders" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<p>For two hours, seven entrepreneurs pitched their ideas and offerings to an expert jury at TiE Bangalore’s first startup showcase of 2016, in the fin-tech sector. Free to the public, the event drew over 120 attendees, and the discussion carried over long into the networking session. (See also YourStory’s coverage of TiE Bangalore’s earlier startup events <a href="http://yourstory.com/tag/tie-bangalore/" target="_blank">here.</a>)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.xpensemanager.com/" target="_blank">XpenseManager</a> is an on-demand expense management platform which lets employees log in and track expenses such as travel reimbursement claims via mobiles. The tool brings in more convenience for employees over existing paper-based approaches, and helps managers track expenses and set spending policies.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176676" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/XpenseManager.jpg" alt="XpenseManager" width="800" height="560" /></p>
<p>Founder Deepa Ramanujam cited data which showed that 56 per cent of mid-market companies surveyed say they have limited visibility into travel and expense spending, and 35 per cent report non-compliant travel expenses. A handful of customers have already been roped in for early stage rollout.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.aisces.com/" target="_blank">Aisces</a> is a cloud-based mobile payment platform based on host card emulation (HCE) and tokenisation. The founder, Anuj Pachoree, is a B.Tech. from IIT BHU and PGSEM from IIM Bangalore, and was earlier with Ezetap and Samsung.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176683" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Aisces.jpg" alt="Aisces" width="800" height="427" /></p>
<p>Banks in India currently issue cards in the plastic medium; Aisces provides a mobile app along with a cloud-based token vault to make this offering virtual. This can be used for applications like ticketing and loyalty programmes. Using Aisces, an Android phone can effectively act as a NFC contactless debit/credit card.</p>
<p>Users are charged a monthly rental of Rs 180 per card. In India, RBI has issued a directive supporting adoption of contactless cards, and SBI and ICICI have already entered this space. Anuj claims there is good growth and acquisition potential in this sector, eg. LoopPay was acquired by Samsung, and Softcard was acquired by Google.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.fxkart.com/" target="_blank">FxKart</a> is an online foreign-exchange platform connecting forex customers and moneychangers. Customers can choose moneychangers based on nearest, cheapest and delivery time filters. The platform provides transparent bidding tools for customers to view and choose the best offers from moneychangers.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176679" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/FxKart.jpg" alt="FxKart" width="800" height="492" /></p>
<p>The market is highly fragmented in India, with over two thousand money changers. The target audience is not the large corporates but SMEs, students and independent travellers. An estimated 300,000 Indian students travel abroad each year, out of 18 million travellers departing from India.</p>
<p>FxKart claims its competitors Nafex and BookMyForex do not offer features such as multiple quotes. Its CEO Abdul Hadi has over 10 years of business advisory experience in Ernst &amp; Young and PWC.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.finmitra.com/" target="_blank">FinMitra</a> is a goal-based financial advisory and management services firm. It helps individuals set financial goals, discover their risk profiles, and find the best investment portfolios in terms of mutual funds and fixed deposits.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176681" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/FinMitra.jpg" alt="FinMitra" width="800" height="532" /></p>
<p>The site is going live this month, and will use analytics to conduct portfolio reviews and offer performance alerts. Market drivers are increase in average household income, increase in financial awareness and a favourable investment environment. The target market is the current pool of about 40 million individual investors in India, estimated to reach 60 million by 2020, according to co-founder Bhargavi Sridharan, an SPJIM graduate who was earlier with Tata Steel and TISS.</p>
<p>OnUs offers a cashless payment service in relatively closed environments where the payments are faster, secure and easier to handle. These include college campuses, corporate canteens and hospitals. Typical purchase items include food, stationery and transport, where purchase amounts are less than Rs 200.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176677" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Onus.jpg" alt="Onus" width="800" height="434" /></p>
<p>Typical credit cards and mobile options may not be suitable here due to reasons of time and cost per transaction; top-up tap-and-pay cards are the best option. OnUs claims to be doing two lakh transactions a month, expected to increase to 3.5 lakh transactions in February.</p>
<p>The founding team includes K.S. Ravi Shankar who was formerly with WoodStock Ambience, Modi Xerox and Wipro; G.G. Srinivas, formerly with ABN AMRO, Kotak Mahindra Bank and  Standard Chartered Bank; and Hari Haran, formerly at SCB Singapore and Barclays India.</p>
<p><a href="https://coinsecure.in/" target="_blank">CoinSecure,</a> founded by Mohit Kalra and Benson Samuel, is a bitcoin platform for trading and exchange in the India market. It aims to reduce the hurdles customers face in Indian rupee compatibility and block chain access.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176682" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/CoinSecure.jpg" alt="CoinSecure" width="800" height="353" /></p>
<p>CoinSecure’s development centre is in Bengaluru, with the head office in Delhi and marketing office in Mumbai. Its offerings include a bitcoin wallet and exchange. Coinsecure.info allows users to search the bitcoin public ledger or blockchain in realtime. For customer education, the company has launched a series of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLuMm4g0xs5W9R70gXNjlGeZHPklsMAjKR" target="_blank">online tutorials</a>.</p>
<p>Bitcoin is not illegal in India, clarified COO Jincy Samuel. In addition to the consumer sector, other use case scenarios include Internet of Things (IoT), where bitcoin can be used by devices to charge for data in nano-transactions.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.mymoneysage.in/" target="_blank">MyMoneySage</a> is a CRM platform for financial services, and is targeted at individuals as well as financial advisors. Advisors can manage their clients efficiently and get visibility among the investor community, said founder Kishorkumar Ballipalli.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176678" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/MyMoneySage.jpg" alt="MyMoneySage" width="800" height="624" /></p>
<p>Investors can get advice on managing their money, with tips on savings and budgets. The platform offers visualisation and alerting tools for investors, along with periodic reminders and actionable insights.</p>
<p><strong>Discussion</strong></p>
<p>While this was a startup showcase and not really a competition or awards event, the jury asked a range of incisive questions (see also my <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/12/finalists-anthah-prerana-startup-competition-40-questions/" target="_blank">Startup Question Bank</a> from the Anthah Prerana startup competition and <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/12/great-startup-pitch-tie-bangalore-finalists/" target="_blank">Tips for Successful Pitches</a>). The jury members were Arvind Tiwary, CEO of SangEnnovate; Suryaprakash Konanuru, CTO at Ideaspring Capital; Parag Dhol, Managing Director at Inventus Capital Partners; and Ganapathy Venugopal, CEO of Axilor.</p>
<p>Here is my pick of 10 questions from the wide-ranging discussion, which will be useful for other fin-tech startups entering this space as well.</p>
<ol>
<li>What regulatory changes may pose a challenge to your model?</li>
<li>How are you dealing with risks of security breaches to consumer and merchant devices?</li>
<li>How will your startup compete with the larger banks when they enter this space?</li>
<li>How are you addressing consumer concerns over data privacy and parental control?</li>
<li>How will you keep per-transaction pricing low and yet attain profitability in a sustainable manner?</li>
<li>How effectively does your platform integrate with back-end systems in large banks and finance companies?</li>
<li>Can you make this process even simpler for the end consumer?</li>
<li>How will you cover up for lost devices or forgotten passwords?</li>
<li>What kinds of new algorithmic insights are you capable of generating?</li>
<li>Your model assumes individuals are rational creatures, but how will you deal with the more common irrational behaviours?</li>
</ol>
<p>With India set to become one of the largest Internet and mobile markets in the world, the potential for profits in fin-tech seems alluring for a wide range of startups. Success will come to those who can successfully answer the tough questions such as the ones posed above, ride the regulatory changes, time their offerings to the right audiences, and build out their teams for high-growth trajectories.</p>
<p><em>Feature image: <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/" target="_blank">shutterstock</a></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/tie-bangalore-showcase-startups-fin-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Qriyo Infolabs raises $160k from Idein Ventures in seed funding</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/qriyo-infolabs-idein-ventures-funding/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/qriyo-infolabs-idein-ventures-funding/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 06:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Press Trust of India]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bengaluru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Idein Ventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mudit Jain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mumbai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rishabh Jain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Serial entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176668</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Technology-based learning platform Qriyo Infolabs said that it has raised a seed funding of USD 160,000 from UAE-based early stage venture capital firm, Idein Ventures. It is currently active in Jodhpur and is in the process of expansion to Mumbai and Bengaluru. Jointly founded by IIT Bombay alumni Mudit Jain, with 4 years of working experience [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Technology-based learning platform Qriyo Infolabs said that it has raised a seed funding of USD 160,000 from UAE-based early stage venture capital firm, Idein Ventures.</p>
<figure id="attachment_164988" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/yourstory-investment1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-164988" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/yourstory-investment1.jpg" alt="Image: Shutterstock" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Image: Shutterstock</figcaption></figure>
<p>It is currently active in Jodhpur and is in the process of expansion to Mumbai and Bengaluru.</p>
<p>Jointly founded by IIT Bombay alumni Mudit Jain, with 4 years of working experience with MNCs like Finmechanics and PWC, and serial entrepreneur Rishabh Jain, Qriyo offers courses at home from wide domains including academics, extracurricular and fitness.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/qriyo-infolabs-idein-ventures-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>[App Fridays] Dekkoh brings professional stylists, online and offline stores and ‘Haute couture’ to your pocket</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/app-fridays-dekkoh/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/app-fridays-dekkoh/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 06:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harshith Mallya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All Things Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aditya Chalasani]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anirudh Dasu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app fridays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app-friday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apparel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dekkoh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Footwear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Haute couture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jewellery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stylist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Varun Mathew]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176579</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Imagine being able to have 24*7 access to a personal stylist and a comprehensive list of online and offline shopping resources. The founders of Dekkoh will have you believe that you need look no further than their mobile-only app that lets users browse fashion products across categories such as apparel, footwear, jewellery, and accessories from [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine being able to have 24*7 access to a personal stylist and a comprehensive list of online and offline shopping resources. The founders of Dekkoh will have you believe that you need look no further than their mobile-only app that lets users browse fashion products across categories such as apparel, footwear, jewellery, and accessories from both online and offline stores. By focussing on both online and offline channels, they aim to give users more variety in terms of style, quality, and price points.</p>
<h2><b>Story so far</b></h2>
<figure id="attachment_176581" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YourStory-App-Fridays-Dekkoh.jpg"><img class="wp-image-176581 size-full" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YourStory-App-Fridays-Dekkoh.jpg" alt="YourStory-App-Fridays-Dekkoh" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The team</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Co-founded by</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Aditya Chalasani (27) and Varun Mathew (27), the Dekkoh team currently comprises seven members. Aditya is a University of Southern California graduate and was working for Oracle in California before coming back to India to co-found Citizens for Accountable Governance (CAG), under Prashant Kishor, which worked on Narendra Modi&#8217;s 2014 election campaign. Post the elections, he co-founded Dekkoh with Varun. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Varun, an NLSIU grad and a 2012 Angela Merkel fellow, was working in the Private Equity(PE) sector till 2014 before joining a micro-finance company. He decided to co-found Dekkoh to help bring SMBs online. Anirudh Dasu (25), a graduate from BITS Pilani, and a full-stack developer is Dekkoh’s CTO. Prior to joining Dekkoh, he worked with a major app development firm in Bengaluru. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The startup was bootstrapped until June 2015. At one point, they just had a couple of months of runway left. Inspired by </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://growthhackers.com/growth-studies/airbnb" target="_blank">Airbnb’s ‘cereal hustle story</a>&#8216;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, they pitched for and landed an association with the Ministry of Tourism to distribute ‘hitchhiker&#8217;s maps to tourists’ across five international airports in India. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Varun adds,</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The funds we raised from that exercise have helped us build our team and product, and we are now looking to raise an investment round for expansion.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dekkoh released their MVP in December 2015, and currently claim to have about 2,000 users, 87 stores and several hundred personal stylists on their platform</span><b>. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Going forward, they aim to grow their user base and tie up with more offline and online stores. Another feature in the pipeline is an option for ‘Trials at home’.</span></p>
<h2><b>How does it work?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YourStory-App-Fridays-Dekkoh2.png"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-176611" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YourStory-App-Fridays-Dekkoh2.png" alt="YourStory-App-Fridays-Dekkoh2" width="350" height="596" /></a>On downloading Dekkoh and logging in, users are taken through a short three-to-four-question quiz that helps the app understand the customer’s style preferences. Then, on the next screen, users are given access to different style options such as ‘Runner’s Digest’, ‘Beach Holiday’, ‘Party On’, and ‘Be Date Ready’. There are custom options for men and women too. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The app also includes an ‘Ask a stylist’ tab where users can make a personal styling request based on the occasion and their budget, add additional details if needed, and get responses from professional stylists. Dekkoh currently has a small team of internal stylists, an external network of vetted stylists and stylists handpicked by store owners. Varun explains, “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">A number of offline and online stores have appointed their own personal stylists on Dekkoh – so the platform is vibrant with lots of players from the fashion industry.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After a user has decided on a product, they can either buy the product through the app or if the store is located in their vicinity, they can call up and visit the store themselves. The app allows users to check if the particular product they are interested in is in stock.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To help with organic growth and ensure stickiness, the app also encourages users to review a store and invite their friends onto the app and rewards them with ‘Karma points’ that are redeemable at local pubs. Dekkoh earns a commission from the stores for every successful transaction on their platform. In the future, they aim to include more premium features and monetise through other channels such as subscription plans. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As they cater to both men and women, Dekkoh has noticed a few patterns based on user behaviour. Varun explains, </span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Women spend a lot of time on the platform and generally do a lot more research and have more questions compared to men, who generally proceed with their transactions faster. We have also seen significant interest from Tier II cities, which do not have local outlets for some of the premium products available online.</span></p></blockquote>
<h2><b>Sector overview</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fashion is estimated to be a $35 billion market in India. As a sector, fashion has gone through a lot of changes in India, and most players are now focussing on personalisation. </span><a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/08/roposo-funding-tiger-global/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tiger Global backed Roposo</span></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">positions itself as a fashion-focussed social media platform. Voonik, which was one of the early starters in this space in India</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/06/voonik-funding/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised $5</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> million</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">from Sequoia Capital and Seedfund in June 2015, focusses on personal fashion recommendations for women. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Limeroad, a social discovery platform for women, had </span><a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/03/limeroad-series-c-30-million/" target="_blank"><span style="font-weight: 400;">raised a $30 million Series C</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> round from Tiger Global and other existing investors in March 2015. Mobile-focussed fashion discovery platform <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/02/wooplr-raises-5-m-funding-from-helion-ventures/" target="_blank">Wooplr raised $5 million</a> from Helion Ventures in February 2015. Then there are e-commerce platforms such as Myntra and Jabong, which have gone from pure-play marketplaces to platforms that focus on personalisation, with Myntra also having its own product lines. Dekkoh and <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/11/shopsense-fynd/" target="_blank">Kae Capital backed Fynd</a> are among the most recent players in this sector.</span></p>
<h2><b><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YourStory-App-Fridays-Dekkoh3.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-176613" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/YourStory-App-Fridays-Dekkoh3.jpg" alt="YourStory-App-Fridays-Dekkoh3" width="350" height="598" /></a>What we liked</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dekkoh has an easy-to-use interface, and makes good use of relevant images and tabs to ensure that fashion discovery and shopping on a smartphone are interesting experiences. The app will appeal to both amateur and experienced shoppers looking to make purchases online. The personal stylist section is also well-thought-out and executed. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The app caters to the needs of both men and women, which is not a very easy task. Most platforms focus on only women. The mix of online and offline stores on the platform gives the end consumers more variety and choice.</span></p>
<h2><b>What could be improved</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Including more categorisation features could make the app more user-friendly. Otherwise, novice shoppers, who do not know what they are looking for may feel overwhelmed. Including more flexible delivery options and ‘same-day’ or ‘next-day delivery’ for hyperlocal stores may increase impulse buys and increase stickiness of the app.</span></p>
<h2><b>YourStory take</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a product, Dekkoh aims to bring online and offline players on one platform and give SMBs a chance to interact with customers more intimately. Also the app is creating a platform for stylists to help end-consumers with their insights and make money in the process. With an experienced team that has hustled their way so far, it will be interesting to see what strategy they follow going forward to further enhance their product and expand their user base.</span></p>
<p>Website: <a href="http://www.dekkoh.co/" target="_blank">Dekkoh.co</a></p>
<p><em>What do you think about this app, do let us know in the comments below. Also do check out other apps under our <a href="http://yourstory.com/tag/app-fridays/" target="_blank">App Fridays</a></em><em> series.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/app-fridays-dekkoh/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>DesignBids, a marketplace for architecture, raises funding from Indian Angel Network</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/designbids-funding/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/designbids-funding/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 05:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Press Trust of India]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ambarish Raghuvanshi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arihant Jain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business incubators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DesignBids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Human Interest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interior design services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup company]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176670</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Delhi-based startup DesignBids, a marketplace for architecture and interior design services, has secured an undisclosed amount of funding from the Indian Angel Network. Angel investors Ambarish Raghuvanshi and Arihant Jain have led this round of investment on behalf of IAN and will join the company board for further mentoring the team. DesignBids is a platform [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Delhi-based startup DesignBids, a marketplace for architecture and interior design services, has secured an undisclosed amount of funding from the Indian Angel Network.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176671" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/yourstory-interior-design.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176671" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/yourstory-interior-design.jpg" alt="Image: Pixabay" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Image: <a href="https://pixabay.com/static/uploads/photo/2015/11/07/21/29/living-1032733_960_720.jpg" target="_blank">Pixabay</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Angel investors Ambarish Raghuvanshi and Arihant Jain have led this round of investment on behalf of IAN and will join the company board for further mentoring the team.</p>
<p>DesignBids is a platform that connects projects owners with architects and interior designers by using a reverse-auction mechanism, very similar to the floating of tenders, which is commonly practised for government projects.</p>
<p>The company was founded in November 2015, and DesignBids has acquired over a 100 projects with 300 designers registered on the website.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/designbids-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital marketing for startups</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/startups-digital-marketing/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/startups-digital-marketing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 03:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Guest Author]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing & Sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Viewpoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-commerce website]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth Hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mailchimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[market research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Viral phenomenon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176643</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The most exhilarating experience is starting your own venture. Some of the big questions that follow are how to reach masses, how to make your business resonate, how to drive your business results, how to be successful, and how to fulfil your dreams with a shoestring budget? Let’s begin with a very basic question, why [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The most exhilarating experience is starting your own venture. Some of the big questions that follow are how to reach masses, how to make your business resonate, how to drive your business results, how to be successful, and how to fulfil your dreams with a shoestring budget?</p>
<p>Let’s begin with a very basic question, <strong>why do startups need marketing</strong>? Startups solve problems for their users, and connecting with right users is about personalised marketing at scale. They need to build their own brand identity and a slow growth in this fast-paced competitive world can be detrimental to the startup’s health.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176645" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Digital-marketing-for-start.jpg" alt="Digital-marketing-for-start" width="800" height="400" /></p>
<p><strong>Why digital marketing and not traditional forms of marketing?</strong> In digital marketing, there are organic ways to grow your consumer base without incurring large amounts of money, it has low entry barriers and scale. A lot can be done with less and sharp targeting leading to less wastage.</p>
<p><strong>As a startup,</strong> <strong>how can digital marketing help you? </strong>It builds awareness and positions your company and brand. It builds a consistent flow of traffic, gets the first few users. This form of marketing also drive leads and online sales.</p>
<p>Keeping the budget constraints in mind, startups need a few techniques/tools that they can use with minimal cost. Let’s look at some of these tools and what can be done to approach these.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>SEO – </strong>This is cost-effective with measurable, long-term benefits. It increases the visibility and organic traffic to the website. Using this, there is free branding and it builds trust and credibility. A big advantage is that it opens your business 24*7.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What needs to be done to be SEO friendly? – </strong> Make your site mobile friendly and secure, especially if is an e-commerce website. Do ensure all pages are working, use appropriate tags/headers/descriptions. Optimise for faster page load times, create good content on the site, and focus on online PR – get users to talk about your site.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Content marketing</strong> – This generates more traffic, more leads, and builds brand awareness. It also builds relationship with current and prospective clients.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What to focus in content marketing</strong>? – Publish great and relevant content on a regular basis. Formulate unique selling proposition. Set up a blog, tell stories, and work with other publishers to post your content/write-ups. Also communicate user stories.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Social media marketing</strong> – This is cost-effective and a platform to build voice. It is way to engage with current and future customers. Pick the right platforms as per your business – Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Google Plus, Tumblr, Pinterest, and Instagram.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What shall you do on the platforms? – </strong>Think about why someone would become a part of your community or follow you (what is in it for me). Seed the platform with the first few pieces of content. Let the users take over, while you monitor. Do use groups/Q&amp;A/chat effectively.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Email marketing </strong>– This is simple, cost-effective, personal, customisable, and measurable with high ROI. You can communicate with an audience of any size. Email has nearly three times as many user accounts as Facebook and Twitter combined.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>How to go about email marketing? – </strong>Identify a service provider. Do-it-yourself platforms are good, few are: Constant Contact, MailChimp, Aweber, Amazon SES. Set up a calendar and very important is that ‘do not always sell’ – majority of the email should be about free service.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong>Growth hacking</strong> – This is low-cost and innovative alternative to traditional marketing.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>How to go about it?</strong> – Offer something for free, set up a referral programme, and go with exclusivity. There should be an element that helps your product go viral.</p>
<p>Try these techniques, start right and let success follow you.</p>
<p><strong>About the Author:</strong></p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-176644" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Amitabh-Verma.jpg" alt="Amitabh-Verma" width="120" height="147" />Amitabh Verma is the CEO and Founder of AMP Digital, a firm into the online training and agency space. He is a business leader with extensive experience in Digital Marketing, Sales, Operations and Customer Service and has worked for global MNCs as well as startups. He is an MBA from IIM, Kozhikode and has done his masters in Economics from the Delhi School of Economics.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/startups-digital-marketing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jupiter Capital invests $2M in Altigreen Propulsion Labs</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/altigreen-funding/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/altigreen-funding/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 03:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Press Trust of India]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altigreen Propulsion Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bengaluru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Engines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hybrid technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hybrid vehicle drivetrain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hybrid vehicle technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jupiter Capital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mumbai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[niche startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sudhakar Gande]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology-enabled solutions]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176673</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Bengaluru-based Jupiter Capital has invested USD 2 million (about Rs 13 crore) in Altigreen Propulsion Labs, a niche startup providing technology-enabled solutions for electric and hybrid powertrains. Jupiter Capital is looking to invest in game-changing technology ventures focused on Make in India, Design in India, and Smart City, the company said in a statement in [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bengaluru-based Jupiter Capital has invested USD 2 million (about Rs 13 crore) in Altigreen Propulsion Labs, a niche startup providing technology-enabled solutions for electric and hybrid powertrains.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176674" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/yourstory-future-transport.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176674" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/yourstory-future-transport.jpg" alt="Image: Deviantart" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Image: <a href="http://morfiuss.deviantart.com/art/Sport-coupe-concept-57299509" target="_blank">Deviant Art</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Jupiter Capital is looking to invest in game-changing technology ventures focused on Make in India, Design in India, and Smart City, the company said in a statement in Mumbai.</p>
<p>&#8220;Altigreen has developed hybrid technology enabling every vehicle to become a hybrid. The patented technology of the company can be easily replicated in other developing nations to address growing concerns on greenhouse gas emission,&#8221; Jupiter Capital&#8217;s Director Sudhakar Gande said.</p>
<p>The solution developed by the company is innovative at a price point, enabling accelerated adoption, he added. Altigreen is engaged in research, design and development of proprietary hybrid vehicle technology for Indian market.</p>
<p>It develops kits to improve fuel-efficiency (~30 per cent) and reduce harmful tailpipe emissions (~25 per cent), not just for new vehicles but also for the large population of existing cars and trucks. Altigreen has four co-founders and is supported by a strong engineering team and an advisory panel of cross-domain industry experts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/altigreen-funding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>This private banker and his father have built a brand for manufacturing your dream luxury car</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/hradyesh-kumar-namdeo-hi/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/hradyesh-kumar-namdeo-hi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 03:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sindhu Kashyap]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car manufacturing brand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[car-manufacturing process]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[end-product]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Founder Director and CEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hand-built luxury car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hradyesh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[luxury car brands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[luxury car sales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manufacturing setups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes Benz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercedes-Benz Maybach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philipp von Sahr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rolls Royce]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176599</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Step aside Bentley Azure, Mercedes-Benz Maybach, Rolls Royce Phantom and DC Avanti, and make way for India’s HI Pvt Ltd, a company that focusses on manufacturing made-to-order luxury cars. While we are in the era of made-to-order shoes, suits, jewellery and bags, Hradyesh Kumar Namdeo decided to set up a manufacturing facility for made-to-order luxury [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Step aside Bentley Azure, Mercedes-Benz Maybach, Rolls Royce Phantom and DC Avanti, and make way for India’s HI Pvt Ltd, a company that focusses on manufacturing made-to-order luxury cars. While we are in the era of made-to-order shoes, suits, jewellery and bags, Hradyesh Kumar Namdeo decided to set up a manufacturing facility for made-to-order luxury cars. The idea is to create a global car manufacturing brand that builds its client&#8217;s ‘dream car’.</p>
<p>Incorporated in 2015, this home-grown brand is busy building its own multi-cluster global business offering luxury, handcrafted cars on ‘invitation only’ basis.</p>
<p>“We hand-build a masterpiece crafted especially for you, exactly the way you want, which always remains a single piece in the whole world,” says 36-year-old Hradyesh, Founder Director and CEO of HI Pvt. Ltd. ‘Morris Street’ is their first hand-built luxury car.</p>
<h2><strong>Private banking to manufacturing luxury cars</strong></h2>
<figure id="attachment_176600" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Yourstory-HI.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176600" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Yourstory-HI.jpg" alt="Yourstory-HI" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Morris Street @ Jaipur</figcaption></figure>
<p>After a career of private banking and handling wealth of HNIs and several royal families, Hradyesh realised a preoccupation common to his clientele was collecting luxury and limited editions of art and other products. While they would buy the top luxury brand of cars, Hradyesh realised that building an Indian global luxury brand for cars would work wonders.</p>
<p>“I saw that most individuals had this strong need for exclusiveness of any luxury offering. These were the initial thoughts followed by a global research study that ignited the idea of creating HI as a supreme luxury offering via the ‘masterpiece edition,’” adds Hradyesh.</p>
<p>So, joining hands with his father, M.Lal, who handled various engineering divisions of BHEL for 34 years, Hradyesh started HI. Every HI car is unique and is put together by hand from scratch. The entire car-manufacturing process includes design, structure, machinery, performance, features, and finish, and all other segments are handcrafted as per owner’s preferences.</p>
<h2><strong>Making the orders</strong></h2>
<p>The team says a model is never replicated nor re-manufactured. These cars are built strictly on invitation and not available through regular sales mediums.</p>
<p>Once the request is placed online, the team screens the same and understands what the individual needs. Then is the important step of verifying the idea to see if it is practically possible to build. Hradyesh explains: there could be a request for a car that looks like a butterfly. While this may look great in the museum, it will not serve its practical purpose on the road.</p>
<p>Most of the products are made at the company&#8217;s NCR and Mumbai manufacturing setups. However, if the client is very specific about the kind of machinery they need, the same is sourced. The invitation requests can be placed from anywhere in the globe, but the manufacture of the end-product happens in India.</p>
<h2><strong>Creating a global Indian brand</strong></h2>
<p>HI is currently at the early stage of the business, and is interacting globally to expand the resource team and join hands with relevant global institutions for ideal financial, talent, and technology and infrastructure infusion.</p>
<p>HI claims to have already received more than 300 invitation requests from different parts of the world and is working on some innovative projects. The average cost of a car is close to a million dollars but varies based on customisation.</p>
<p>HI, Hradyesh says, was started with creating a new global market. He adds that it will constantly innovate and create new segments, eliminating presence of any direct competition.</p>
<p><strong>YourStory take</strong></p>
<p>According to credit rating agency ICRA, India’s luxury car sales is believed to touch one lakh from the current 30,000 cars, by 2020. The report further suggested that about 1.8 lakh Indians are considered dollar millionaires and this category is expected to grow at a rapid pace. So it is safe to assume that Indians across the globe are keen purchasers of luxury car brands.</p>
<p>It is interesting to note that the luxury car sales in India was at less than 1.5 per cent of the overall sales, which was much lesser than the global average. Another interesting pointer is the statement by Philipp von Sahr, President, BMW, that along with metro cities, the company sees growth in sales from Tier II and III cities.</p>
<p>However, a growing market means fiercer and stronger competition. An Audi India statement said that in 2014-15 11,292 vehicles were sold and Mercedes Benz claimed to have sold 11,213 vehicles, with both the companies recording a growth of 11.51 and 18 percent respectively from the previous year.</p>
<p>So, with the bigger, much-established global brands themselves fighting it out fiercely in the space, where does HI fall in the space? In a space where the snob value of the product runs deep with the brand name, will HI be able to create its mark? Hradyesh says that they are much different from the Audis and BMWs of the world, as their focus is more on creating a single piece and not even a limited edition.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.hradyesh.com/" target="_blank">Website</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/hradyesh-kumar-namdeo-hi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pune based Canvazify lets you share your thoughts and ideas on ready to use planning templates</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/canvazify/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/canvazify/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 03:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aparajita Choudhury]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abhijit Mhetre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[API]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia Pacific]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boston University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chief of Business Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cigna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud infrastructure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IMS Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PDF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pune University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology_Internet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176603</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In an increasingly tech-savvy world, where time is short and attention spans shorter, no one has the time or inclination to participate in long-drawn out white-boarding discussions. Bulky documents containing details of discussions are also kept aside to read at a later time, and ideas and thoughts are eventually lost in a pile of papers [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In an increasingly <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/07/recruitment-startup-industry/" target="_blank">tech-savvy</a> world, where time is short and attention spans shorter, no one has the time or inclination to participate in long-drawn out <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/10/building-culture-socialcops/" target="_blank">white-boarding</a> discussions. Bulky documents containing details of discussions are also kept aside to read at a later time, and ideas and thoughts are eventually lost in a pile of papers and lack of processes. Bringing people and their ideas together onto the same page is becoming an increasingly difficult task.</p>
<p>During his 12-year-corporate career, Abhijit Mhetre, 39, often noticed how professionals found it challenging to collate weekly <a href="http://yourstory.com/2012/02/freelance-assignments-platform-freelancer-com-launches-indiaportal/" target="_blank">assignments</a> and case studies onto a single platform. This sowed the seeds for the idea to start Canvazify.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176617" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-176617" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Cnvazify-Team.jpg" alt="Canvazify Team" width="800" height="400" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Canvazify Team</figcaption></figure>
<p>Canvazify works like a <a href="http://yourstory.com/2013/11/pinterest-endgame/" target="_blank">Pinterest</a> for team ideas. It is a collaborative platform that helps teams collect, discuss and act on team ideas. Its simple sticky-note-like platform comes with quick-start innovation templates that help teams stay focussed and take informed decisions faster. Canvazify templates are suitable for startup entrepreneurs, product managers, and design/innovation strategy consultants.</p>
<p>Abhijit says,</p>
<blockquote><p>From idea validation to business models and from product roadmaps to competitive analysis, Canvazify serves everything under one umbrella. We have external integration with Chrome, Dropbox, and Trello to flow ideas into Canvazify or from Canvazify to other tools.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Abhijit is a computer science graduate from <a href="http://yourstory.com/2014/09/startup-city-pune/" target="_blank">Pune</a> University. He has worked across three continents as a techno-marketer, large-scale programme manager, strategy consultant, and account manager. He started his career in India with <a href="http://lt-infotech-ltd.yspages.com/" target="_blank">L&amp;T Infotech</a> as a software programmer where he built a wireless mobile banking system for palm-top devices. Post that, he went to the UK and worked for IMS Health as technology consultant followed by a couple of insurance companies such as Travelers, Marsh, Cigna. In 2012, he earned his executive MBA from Boston University.</p>
<h2><strong>Building a great team</strong></h2>
<p>The common challenge that every startup faces is finding the right people. Fortunately, Abhijit knew Akshay Nahar and Niket Puranik, and the three came together to create a great team.</p>
<p>The trio had known each other since college. Akhshay and Niket had not taken the predictable corporate route and had started an <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/100marks-stylish-in-beauty-services-startup/" target="_blank">IT services</a> company for web projects. Today, Akshay is Chief of Business Development and Niket is Chief of Technology at Canvazify.</p>
<h2><strong>Scalability in technology</strong></h2>
<p>Canvazify is built on cloud infrastructure that provides the flexibility to integrate with <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/09/ola-opens-api-integration/" target="_blank">API</a>s. Currently, the startup caters to more than 55 countries. According to Abhijit, 31,000 ideas have been discussed on the Canvazify platform and the majority of users are entrepreneurs, product managers, design/strategic consultants, and educators.</p>
<p>The startup allows users to substantiate ideas with other collateral such as blog links, images, documents, and more. It also let users bring or tag ideas from wherever they work using a Chrome plugin and a mobile app (coming soon). To ensure security, Canvazify conducts the data transfer between the user’s device and the server on the <a href="http://yourstory.com/2011/09/what-is-your-cloud-idea/" target="_blank">Amazon cloud</a>, and it is SSL encrypted.</p>
<blockquote><p>Documents/images from Dropbox can be easily referenced into Canvazify making it easier to use and enriching the user experience. It allows users to export ideas into a PDF or into Trello-like project management software. In a nutshell, users can conceptualise ideas into Canvazify, import them, or export them into other tools to process further. Canvazify will act as a hub for a team’s idea,” says Abhijit.</p></blockquote>
<p>Currently based out of Pune, the startup has a team of five members. Moreover, Canvazify is getting mentored in TiE-Pune and Startup Leadership Program, Pune.</p>
<h2><strong>Monetisation </strong></h2>
<p>Canvazify generates revenues from monthly subscription models at $5 per user. The startup is witnessing approximately 23-25 per cent new user growth month on month. Abhijit says that over 31,000 ideas have been discussed and 2.26 lakhs actions have been tracked, and that number is growing every day. In terms of user base, 45-48 per cent are from India and 55-52 per cent are from US,Brazil, Canada, the UK, Switzerland, Spain, Italy, Germany, Turkey, Japan, Australia, New Zealand, Sweden, and Portugal.</p>
<p>He says, &#8220;We are a bootstrapped venture. We are looking to raise external capital to expand our platform and boost our global presence.&#8221;</p>
<h3><strong>YourStory’s take</strong></h3>
<p>India as a market appears to be growing in terms of the emergence of <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/02/challenges-saas-startup/" target="_blank">SaaS</a>-based task management software, workforce task management, cloud-based collaborative platforms and project management software.</p>
<p>Markets and Markets forecasts that the enterprise collaboration market is expected to grow by $70.61 billion in 2019. In terms of geographies, North America and Europe are expected to be the biggest markets in terms of revenue contribution, while <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/08/facebook-chose-frrole/" target="_blank">Asia-Pacific</a> (APAC) and Europe are expected to experience increased market traction, during the forecast period.</p>
<p>Abhijit says that Canvazify is wrongly compared with many communication and task management platforms like Slack, <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/10/sortd-app/" target="_blank">Trello</a>, Asana, and others. Canvazify allows actionable ideas to flow into tools such as Trello and Jeera. The startup’s competitors are global players like ideascale, Mural.ly, Spigit and MindMeister. Right now, Canvazify plans to go big in the US and Europe regions considering their inclination towards the tech enabled collaborative platforms.</p>
<p><a href="http://canvazify.com/" target="_blank">Canvazify</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/canvazify/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why entrepreneurs should focus on value rather than valuation</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/entrepreneur-startup-valuation/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/entrepreneur-startup-valuation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 03:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sripati Acharya]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baidu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entrepreneurial finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pre-money valuation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Private equity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robin Li]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TermSheet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valuation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venture capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176538</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Twenty years from now, you will be more disappointed by the things that you didn&#8217;t do than by the ones you did do. So throw off the bowlines. Sail away from safe harbor. Catch the trade winds in your sails. Explore, Dream, Discover.&#8221; Mark Twain. As a seed stage investor, I come across many entrepreneurs [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8220;Twenty years from now, you will be more disappointed by the things that you didn&#8217;t do than by the ones you did do. So throw off the bowlines. Sail away from safe harbor. Catch the trade winds in your sails. Explore, Dream, Discover.&#8221; <a href="http://www.dumblittleman.com/2011/03/7-life-changing-lessons-you-can-learn.html" target="_blank">Mark Twain</a>.</p></blockquote>
<p>As a seed stage investor, I come across many entrepreneurs and they come in all shapes and sizes. Above everything, I admire their courage, tenacity, and willingness to do something new Apart from these qualities that make entrepreneurs stand out, a lot of factors go into making a successful startup. Some factors that cannot be controlled by entrepreneurs include market timing and luck. However, an entrepreneur can make a choice between focusing on valuation and value.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/yourstory-valuation-and-funding-feature.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-176639" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/yourstory-valuation-and-funding-feature.jpg" alt="yourstory-valuation-and-funding-feature" width="800" height="400" /></a></p>
<p>Valuation is an important aspect and something that entrepreneurs needs to pay careful attention to at the time of fundraising. It is a thorny issue that comes up while raising the initial capital, and then at each subsequent round. However, a manic focus on valuation boomerangs in unexpected ways and can ultimately destroy value.</p>
<p>Let’s say there’s an early-stage company that has previously raised some initial funding, is seeing good traction, and is now ready for the next round. They have had very positive conversations with VCs and two offers on the table. The first one is for a $5 million raise on $15 million pre-money valuation. This will result in a post-money valuation of $20 million with a 25 per cent dilution. The competing offer is for a $10 million raise at a $20 million pre-valuation. This results in a 33 per cent dilution at a post-money valuation of $30 million. Which one is the better offer?</p>
<p>In order to answer that let’s fast forward to the next funding round, which would typically happen within 12–18 months post the previous round. In case of the first offer, for existing investors to not have a down round, the funding needs to occur at a minimum $30 million valuation, which is the post-money valuation of the company. And for it to be considered a positive event for the company, at least a 50 per cent bump up from the previous round. This makes it a $45 million pre-money round.</p>
<p>In the second case, it is a $20 million post-money round and a good outcome is a pre-money valuation of $30 million.</p>
<p>The difference here, between $30 and $45 million valuation, is significant. What might be a short and heavily contested fund raise with multiple term sheets at $35 million can become a long fund raise cycle at $45 million. This can have a negative effect on moral of the founders and employees and restrict growth investment during the fundraise.</p>
<p>In other words, there is smaller margin for error when raising a larger round at a higher valuation. Not that raising money at higher valuations is bad, but it should be done with the complete understanding that the built-in expectations are higher to deliver higher results, faster. It also has implications on valuation expectations for subsequent funding rounds.</p>
<p>When Baidu.com went public in 2005, it opened at $27. It ended the day, however, rising more than 350 per cent, at $122. The story goes that the founder, Robin Li, instead of being over the moon, was worried. Why? Because he was prepared for running a company with expectations consistent with a $27 share price, not $122. Baidu has done well since then – now at a split adjusted $2,000 – nevertheless illustrates that increased valuation doesn’t come for free.</p>
<p>As an entrepreneur, focussing on value is prudent – value that is being delivered to the customer, value which is created in the company from sustainable differentiation, value that the end customer is willing to pay the desired price for.</p>
<p>Valuation is a side effect of all of these efforts.</p>
<p>Valuation is heavily dependent on market conditions. It is a function of supply and demand for funds in the market. The same company could have a valuation that is two times in a ‘hot’ market with identical metrics than at other times. Valuation, for this reason, can be a dangerously misleading success metric – one that the entrepreneur has little control over, yet one which is the most visible externally as well as within the company.</p>
<p>For an entrepreneur, it is much better to focus on something that is under their control versus linking success to something that is not.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/entrepreneur-startup-valuation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What do I eat at this restaurant? Confused? Ask Ketchupp</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/ketchupp/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/ketchupp/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 03:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sindhu Kashyap]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[FoodTech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chandigarh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food-related products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ketchupp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online food ordering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recommender system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trusted friend network]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176602</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Foodtech, food recommendations, and food delivery seem all the rage these days. Even with the number of players in this space, there always seems to be room for more. The market appears to be shifting towards recommendations made via social and chat platforms like Siri and Google Now. Pune-based Quinto and the latest entrant – Gurgaon-based [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Foodtech, food recommendations, and food delivery seem all the rage these days. Even with the number of players in this space, there always seems to be room for more. The market appears to be shifting towards recommendations made via social and chat platforms like Siri and Google Now. <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/12/quinto-siri-for-food-and-restaurant-recommendations/" target="_blank">Pune-based Quinto</a> and the latest entrant – Gurgaon-based Ketchupp are focussed on giving recommendations.</p>
<p>Both startups believe that while there are several platforms that focus on aggregating different restaurants, chefs, curation of menus and food delivery, few actually help the consumers get the food they need at the restaurants.</p>
<p>Everyone has faced confusion when deciding what to order or what a restaurant is famous for. Ketchupp aims to help solve this problem. Ketchupp says it enables its users to have the best meals every time anywhere. Based on the same principle as most recommendation apps, Ketchupp uses natural language programming and consumer recommendations to offer insights.</p>
<p>The team says their vision is to be a personalised recommendation platform for dishes where users are recommended dishes basis their personal preferences, behaviours, climate and demographics.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176604" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Yourstory-Ketchupp.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176604" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Yourstory-Ketchupp.jpg" alt="Yourstory-Ketchupp" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The core team @ Ketchupp</figcaption></figure>
<h2><strong>Starting by the book</strong></h2>
<p>Narender Kumar and Chirag Taneja had been friends for a while, and like most friends, they liked exploring the best places to eat around Delhi. Chirag went through a surgery, which reduced his appetite. Being food buddies, the duo would end up eating together most of the time and almost always found a blind spot when it came to what to order at different restaurants.</p>
<p>While most platforms like <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/2015-lessons-zomato/" target="_blank">Zomato would recommend</a> or give them options on the best restaurant to go to, the duo didn&#8217;t know what to eat there. They decided to write a book on where to find the best food in the city.</p>
<p>However, they found the task time-consuming and un-scalable. It was then that they decided to invite people from across the city to explore different restaurants and give their insights based on their dining experiences. They formed a Facebook group called the KetchuppGang.</p>
<p>“On the group, people shared their experiences, opinions and views on different dishes at different restaurants. We thought why not automate the process and get real-time results; thus the idea of building a mobile app came into being,” says 30-year-old Chirag.</p>
<p>Rahul Makkar, a hotel management graduate with a cult social media following, and deep insights about food joined the team early on. Bipin Taneja came onboard to handle restaurant alliances and events.</p>
<p>Knowing that they needed to build a strong tech team, they brought Abdul Khalid an IIT Delhi alumnus on board. He decided to take the plunge from Housing to join in as the co-founder of Ketchupp.</p>
<p>“All of us share a common theme of discovering #YahanBestKyaMiltaHai. Most of all, we believe one can find the best dishes only if one has the drive to cook themselves. So one of our key requirements in the job description is that you should know how to cook or should have a chef in you,” adds Chirag.</p>
<h2><strong>Workings of the product</strong></h2>
<p>Their MVP aggregated the views of different people, which helped consumers find the best dishes around them at different restaurants. So when someone asks the app what they can eat at any place, the best recommendations come up.</p>
<p>Citing an example, Chirag says, if someone wants to have the best <em>masala dosa</em> in their area, they can ask for it and instantly get results for <em>masala dosa</em> in their location based on people’s recommendations.</p>
<p>Ketchupp aggregates all social media feeds and social blogs, analyses them and makes instant recommendations. These recommendations are in turn validated by your trusted friend network, bringing credibility to the recommendations.</p>
<p>“For instance, Berry Pulao is a “Must Try” at Soda Bottle Opener Wala is an outcome of our algorithm, which is also validated by your friend network who use the app and recommend it,” says Chirag.</p>
<p>So like in the example, if the Berry Pulao has been recommended by the algorithm, the user also gets a list of friends in his or her social network who recommend the same dish.</p>
<h2><strong>Growth and traction</strong></h2>
<p>The team launched their Android app in November 2015, which has since been downloaded more than 1,000 times in the Gurgaon area. Ketchupp will be launching their iOS app soon.</p>
<p>Ketchupp claims to have partnered with all food festivals in Delhi like the Asian Hawkers Market, Palate Fest 2015 and Delhi Cocktail Week, where they claim to have given the fest a mobile outlook and helped visitors decide #YahanBestKyaMiltaHain.</p>
<p>The team is currently bootstrapped and has raised a small round of investment from family and friends. They are planning to raise funds from investors who can also offer mentorship and guidance.</p>
<p>The team is planning to increase the number of dishes they recommend from 3,000 to 15,000 soon and then further increase this number exponentially to 2,00,000 dishes in a year’s time. In the next three months, they will cover more cities in North India focussing on delicacies from Amritsar, Ludhiana, Chandigarh, Jammu and Kashmir, Lucknow, Shimla, and Manali. The team also plans to be a lead-generation platform for the likes of Zomato and Swiggy.</p>
<h2><strong>YourStory take</strong></h2>
<p>The Siri for X, Google Now for X, chat based and other recommendation engines seem to be ruling the roost. And they seem to have hit that most popular of all startup ideas – food.</p>
<p>In October last year, the delivery startup MagicTiger acquired AI-based startup Zoyo to help users shop over chat. With this acquisition, MagicTiger will now answer consumers’ questions on food and other food-related products.</p>
<p>Pune-based Quinto raised an undisclosed amount from <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/08/faasos-food-tech-120-cr-revenues/" target="_blank">Faasos Founder Jaydeep Burman</a>. Ketchupp follows the a similar recommendation based model, and this too is yet to see revenues; app downloads and Facebook page members cannot be considered a mode of traction and growth. With investors and the market increasingly looking for revenue models, it will become important for Ketchupp to focus on growth and traction.</p>
<p>Also, with players like <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/swiggy-funding/" target="_blank">Swiggy raising more funding,</a> the possibility of them entering the personalised chat recommendation model is high. They are already venturing into different modules of social recommendations of their own. Not only do these players have deeper pockets, they already have a strong base of restaurant tie ups and partnerships.</p>
<p>While the demand is there – food services is estimated to be a $50 billion market – issues of scale plague this sector. Companies like TinyOwl have borne the brunt of scaling up too soon. Also, these young startups are burning up a lot of investor cash in their quest for growth, as evidenced by the many rounds of funding companies have raised in a short period of time.</p>
<p>The question is whether Ketchupp can fight its competition and the bigger players or not.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ketchupp.in/" target="_blank">Website</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/ketchupp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Their startup aims to provide affordable health at your fingertips</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/healthenablr/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/healthenablr/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 02:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tarush Bhalla]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avishek Mukherjee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bamasish Paul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healthcare startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthenablr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lybrate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Practo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qikwell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telemedicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Chicago]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176618</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The year was 2013. Bamasish Paul, 39 and Avishek Mukherjee, 36 were pursuing their MBA at the University of Chicago and working on their final-year project. Being a part of the project (study) group, they created a doctor networking portal. Prior to this, Avishek was working in healthcare analytics, and had held senior positions with [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year was 2013. Bamasish Paul, 39 and Avishek Mukherjee, 36 were pursuing their MBA at the University of Chicago and working on their final-year project. Being a part of the project (study) group, they created a doctor networking portal.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176620" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Healthenablr-Co-founders-L-to-R-Bamasish-Paul-and-Avishek-Mukherjee.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176620" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Healthenablr-Co-founders-L-to-R-Bamasish-Paul-and-Avishek-Mukherjee.jpg" alt="Healthenablr Co-founders (L to R) - Bamasish Paul and Avishek Mukherjee" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Healthenablr Co-founders (L to R) &#8211; Bamasish Paul and Avishek Mukherjee</figcaption></figure>
<p>Prior to this, Avishek was working in healthcare analytics, and had held senior positions with companies like the Mayo Clinic, and Capital BlueCross. Bamasish was working as an investor in AIG Private Equity and Brookfield Equity, where he was handling the real-estate sector.</p>
<p>But why did Bamasish feel the need to make the transition from investor to entrepreneur? He replies:</p>
<blockquote><p>“I think I was getting way too comfortable in my skin. As an investor, you are just a part of someone’s journey. You’re not creating one for your own. I wanted to create my own journey.”</p></blockquote>
<p>After the course finished, Bamasish joined AIG Capital while Avishek went on to become the Chief Technology Officer at Genia Technologies. However, the discussions on their entrepreneurial endeavour continued. After a lot of debate, the idea took the form of Healthenablr – a patient-centric healthcare service that was not only affordable but accessible.</p>
<h2><strong>Enabling health </strong></h2>
<p>Healthenablr is a telemedicine <a href="http://yourstory.com/tag/healthcare-startups/" target="_blank">healthcare</a> services company that is on a mission to make healthcare affordable and accessible across the world. The company has developed a proprietary web- and mobile-centric platform that not only assists patients, but also helps doctors handle and schedule their visits.</p>
<p>Divided into two parts, the first – poccare – is the patient-facing side of the product that allows general patients book video appointments, see a doctor in person or have a live chat with a doctor.  The platform currently allows you to book appointments through their website, Android app or their helpline.</p>
<p>The second – pocclinic – is an advanced clinic management SaaS software provided to doctors to help them manage their day better. Its comprises various offerings – BrandEdge, which deals with acquiring more patients, taking appointment requests and checking the doctor’s availability; RecordPro, which helps doctors manage all their patient records on a secure cloud; and Practice360, which helps doctors expand their practice through offering telemedicine visits.</p>
<p>At present, the platform has a little over 3,700 doctors on the network, spread across Kolkata, and more around the the areas surrounding the city as well as in   Mumbai where the firm is headquartered. The firm also has a network of five in-house doctors and the founders say this number is certain to grow.</p>
<p>By December 2015, the size of the team had grown to 30 with 16 members in customer support while 12 support sales. At the time of December 2015, By last month the firm was closing almost 15 <a href="http://yourstory.com/tag/telemedicine/" target="_blank">telemedicine </a>consultations a day. It had already closed in total of  50 video calls as of November 2015.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176621" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/The-team-at-Healthenablr.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176621" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/The-team-at-Healthenablr.jpg" alt="The team at Healthenablr" width="800" height="413" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The team at Healthenablr</figcaption></figure>
<h2><strong>Costing </strong></h2>
<p>In terms of revenue, the co-founders tell us that 40 per cent of their revenues are generated from the B2B side of the business, with a premium listing of services on BrandEdge costing Rs 250 per month and a basic pocclinic EMR model subscription costing Rs 450 per month.</p>
<p>The focus for the firm clearly seems to be on the B2B side of the business and strengthening their offerings in terms of getting more doctors and specialists on the network before tackling B2C side of the business. In the next three to four months, the firm is also looking at making their specialisation services available 24 *7 to the customers.</p>
<h2><strong><em>YourStory</em> Take  </strong></h2>
<p>According to reports by <a href="http://www.ibef.org/industry/healthcare-india.aspx" target="_blank">IBEF and PwC</a>, the healthcare market in India is valued at $100 billion as of 2015. Following <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/12/healthcare-startup-india-2015/" target="_blank">YourStory Research</a>, investor interest in healthcare has already heightened with as many as 57 deals made last year amounting to $276.5 million, a huge leap from 2014 where 24 deals were made that amounted to $91.6 million.</p>
<p>The heightened activity, scope of increasing profitability, and strong investor focus has also fostered the entry of several players to the market, making the segment a fairly crowded one. Healthenablr will directly compete with the likes of Practo and Lybrate, which are heavily funded and have a strong footing in the market. Moreover, the segment is getting even more heated up with bigger players like Practo on an <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/09/practo-acquires-qikwell/" target="_blank">acquisition spree with Qikwell</a> and <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/09/practo-acquires-insta-health/" target="_blank">Insta Health</a> to kill competition in their space.</p>
<p>Moreover, starting off with Tier II cities might be a good start for the company as a report from IBEF says that rural India, which matches up to 70 per cent of the population, is set to emerge as a demand source of the future.</p>
<p>Despite the positive indicators, Healthenablr, which is still in its early stages, needs to sort out an innovative strategy to get the market, which is getting increasingly saturated.</p>
<p><strong>Website: <a href="https://www.healthenablr.com/patients" target="_blank">www.healthenablr.com</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/healthenablr/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>YourStory meetup for Qualcomm® Design in India Challenge in Gurgaon today</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/qdic-2/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/qdic-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 02:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Team YS]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design in India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hardware design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hardware startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IP protection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mumbai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NASSCOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[product design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qualcomm Innovation Lab in Bangalore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunil Lalvani]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176625</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This article is sponsored by Qualcomm. Here’s a fantastic opportunity for product design and hardware startups to take their ideas and prototypes to the market in 2016. Qualcomm® is looking for path-breaking ideas in these domains and is hosting a series of offline meetups. After Bengaluru and Hyderabad, the Qualcomm team heads to Gurgaon on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This article is sponsored by </em><a href="http://www.qualcomm.co.in/"><em>Qualcomm</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p>Here’s a fantastic opportunity for product design and hardware startups to take their ideas and prototypes to the market in 2016. Qualcomm® is looking for path-breaking ideas in these domains and is hosting a series of offline meetups. After Bengaluru and Hyderabad, the Qualcomm team heads to Gurgaon on 29 Jan, followed by Pune (Monday, 1 Feb) and Mumbai (Tue, 2 Feb) to interact with startups in person.</p>
<p><a href="http://goo.gl/forms/2RblP0h3Fp">Request an invitation to attend a meetup in your city</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/QDIC.png" target="_blank"><img class="alignleft wp-image-176649 size-full" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/QDIC.png" alt="" width="1024" height="513" /></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>Qualcomm® Design in India Challenge</strong></span></p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.qualcomm.co.in/design-in-india"><strong>Qualcomm Design in India Challenge,</strong></a><strong> </strong><strong>in association with NASSCOM,</strong> has set out to discover the best and brightest product design and development companies in the country working on innovative technology that has implications in agriculture, smartphones, IoT/wearables, environment protection/clean technology, and more.</p>
<p><strong>What’s in it for you as a startup?</strong></p>
<p>Up to 10 companies will be shortlisted by March 2016, each of which will win $10,000 in prize money. That’s just the beginning. These companies will then be invited to the <strong>Qualcomm Innovation Lab</strong> in Bangalore, where their ideas will be nurtured and incubated over six months.</p>
<blockquote>
<h3><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wch0qeRZTX0&amp;feature=youtu.be">Click here to see what awaits the chosen few at the Qualcomm Innovation Lab in Bangalore after March</a></h3>
</blockquote>
<p>During this time, the chosen startups will get the type of dedicated technical and engineering support that is simply unavailable anywhere else in the country. Qualcomm promises to provide mentoring and guidance to each shortlisted company to help them take their product to a stage where it is a viable and scalable proposition.</p>
<p><strong>IP protection support</strong></p>
<p>What’s more, Qualcomm has in-house experts to provide the chosen startups all the required guidance on protecting their intellectual property rights as they further develop their product and make it ready for the market.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.qualcomm.co.in/design-in-india/faqs" target="_blank">Click here to read more about the Qualcomm® Design in India Challenge</a></p>
<p>Gurgaon: 29 January</p>
<p>Pune: 01 February</p>
<p>Mumbai: 02 February</p>
<p><a href="http://goo.gl/forms/2RblP0h3Fp">Request an invitation to one of the upcoming offline meetups.</a> Limited slots available.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://youtu.be/nwQsEz7v0HQ">Watch Qualcomm India President Sunil Lalvani talk about how participating companies stand to benefit from the Design in India challenge</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/qdic-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How this 27-year-old experimented with various business models to build a sustainable budget hotel platform</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/qik-stay/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/qik-stay/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 02:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tausif Alam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Startup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business_Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospitality management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hospitality_Recreation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotel chains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OYO Rooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qik Stay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zo Rooms]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176516</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The ideas for the best businesses tend to come from personal experience,” Virgin Founder Richard Branson wrote in a recent Trinidad Guardian blog. Qik Stay came about along similar lines. A few years ago, when Jasveer Singh was looking for a paying guest (PG) accommodation in Gurgaon, he faced various difficulties. This personal experience motivated [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The ideas for the best businesses tend to come from personal experience,” Virgin Founder Richard Branson wrote in a recent Trinidad Guardian blog. Qik Stay came about along similar lines.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176527" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/DSC_0282_new_edited.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176527" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/DSC_0282_new_edited.jpg" alt="Qik Stay team" width="800" height="400" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Qik Stay team</figcaption></figure>
<p>A few years ago, when Jasveer Singh was looking for a paying guest (PG) accommodation in Gurgaon, he faced various difficulties. This personal experience motivated him to enter this segment and root out the problems faced by many like him.</p>
<p>The business idea emerged in the form of Sparehousing.com, a platform that helped property lookers find PG accommodation. He ran the business for some months and pivoted the business model to a guest-house chain. He named this business ZoZo.in.</p>
<p>Around the same time, OYO Rooms was emerging in the hospitality industry. Jasveer observed the operations of this budget hotel marketplace and decided to build something similar.</p>
<p>He again pivoted the model. In January 2015, he and his two co-founders launched ZoZo Stay, an asset-light model wherein guest houses were made available on an hourly basis. However, by July, they rebranded ZoZo Stay as &#8216;Qik Stay&#8217;  due to the similarity between the company&#8217;s name and that of ZO Rooms. It wasn&#8217;t just the name that was changed, however. Jasveer also pivoted the basic business model of his startup. He wanted to become a company that rebrands hotels, and not just aggregates them.</p>
<p>“Budget hotels in the country are as unorganised, and their policies are as translucent as they can get. Even after having an online presence through OTAs (Online Travel Agents), most of the budget hotels neither carry a brand value nor transparency. Although the new-age hotel aggregators are doing a good job in bringing more unorganised hotels online, they’re not solving the problem of quality and trust deficit, thereby making them almost similar to conventional OTAs. We believe with standardised operations and regular quality checks, we can achieve cost-synergies in the medium-to-long term of our partnership with hotels. This will make this co-branding model sustainable compared to the price wars which some of our main competitors are playing,” says Jasveer, who is the CEO of Qik Stay.</p>
<p>Coming from a hospitality background gave him and his team insights into the industry. “We understand what the customers need and we know what the hotel owners want, which basically helps us strategise from a holistic perspective,” Jasveer explains.</p>
<h2><strong>Initial struggles </strong></h2>
<p>It is always a difficult task to find the right talent, especially for a startup. “For me, it was all the more challenging given the fact that I come from a non-tech background. Nonetheless, our strategy of hiring experienced IT professionals and giving them autonomy has been doing just about perfect,” adds Jasveer.</p>
<h2><strong>Growth numbers</strong></h2>
<p>The startup started out with a seed funding of $250,000 from ID Enablers. Initially, it spent the investment in technology and team development. Now, it’s spending on building the brand and taking it out to the public.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Also Read:</strong> <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/07/budget-accommodation-india/" target="_blank">How venture-backed startups are trying to solve the accommodation problem in India</a></p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Gurgaon-based platform claims to have presence in over 60 cities and has partnered with more than 250 hotels. It’s also planning to focus on bulk bookings through corporates.</p>
<p>The platform works with its partner hotels on a revenue-sharing basis, offering a large part of the booking amount to the hotel owner and keeping the remaining part of the pie.</p>
<p>Qik Stay is in talks with a few venture capitalists and plans to raise funds soon for further expansion of operations and marketing.</p>
<h2><strong>Stiff competition </strong></h2>
<p>In the estimated budget hotel aggregation market,  which is anything between $25 and $40 billion, various platforms are vying to grab the larger part of the segment.</p>
<p><a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/05/oyo-rooms-review/" target="_blank">OYO Rooms</a>, <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/wudstay-business-model/" target="_blank">Wudstay</a> and <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/09/stayzilla-travel-social/" target="_blank">Stayzilla</a>, among others, are some of the known players in this segment.</p>
<p>Qik Stay says that it’s looking at capturing close to one-fourth of this market size. Its expected revenue for FY17 is Rs 180 crore.</p>
<p>The platform considers OYO Rooms as its biggest competitor in the industry. “To outstrip them, we’re creating our own category – that is the uppermost layer of the budget hotels market. Our average per-night rate is between Rs 2,000 and 2,500,” says Jasveer.</p>
<p>Customer acquisition is concentrated on the B2B market, capturing the corporate customers of corporate cities. The startup claims that it has 50 companies on-board as its business to venture partners.</p>
<h2><strong>Brand has responsibility </strong></h2>
<p>Jasveer says that maintaining quality in this space is a very big challenge. For this he has assigned people to do regular quality checks and ensure quality throughout.</p>
<h2><strong>YourStory take </strong></h2>
<p>In the past one year, the billion-dollar budget hotel industry has witnessed various developments, from many new players entering the segment, to the rising interest of investors like Tiger Global and Softbank in the industry.</p>
<p>Amidst the buzz, the deal between OYO Rooms and ZO Rooms is a curious case in the industry. The latter entering the segment, raising rounds of funds and now bequeathing the business to OYO raises questions on the business model of the industry.</p>
<p>Besides, many smaller acquisitions have also happened in the industry. In August last year, Wudstay acquired Awesome Stays. During summer last year, Australia-based StayWell Hospitality was also trying to acquire a budget segment Indian hotel chain with plans to invest over Rs 158 crore in hospitality business in India.</p>
<p>It is true late comers in the segment have learned a lot from the mistakes made by their predecessors who went out there in the market to experiment with various models. However, the budget hotel hospitality market is still not foolproof and holds many surprises. With international players also eyeing the market, a new picture is bound to emerge with their entry into the segment.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.qikstay.com/"><strong><em>Website</em></strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/qik-stay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flipkart now launches global sourcing platform for its merchants</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/flipkart-global/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/flipkart-global/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 14:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Radhika P Nair]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alibaba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon.in]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart Global]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paytm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ShopClues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapdeal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176528</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Flipkart has launched a platform that allows its merchants to source products from wholesalers across the world, primarily China, and India. The platform is called Flipkart Global and has been in pilot stage for about a month as per the documents with YourStory. The Bengaluru-based e-commerce major has sent a presentation to its sellers about the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Flipkart has launched a platform that allows its merchants to source products from wholesalers across the world, primarily China, and India. The platform is called Flipkart Global and has been in pilot stage for about a month as per the documents with <strong>YourStory</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/flipkartglobal-01.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-176588 aligncenter" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/flipkartglobal-01.png" alt="flipkartglobal-01" width="800" height="400" /></a></p>
<p>The Bengaluru-based e-commerce major has sent a presentation to its sellers about the new sourcing platform. YourStory is in possession of this document. While the document initially states that Flipkart will give merchants access to a worldwide pool of suppliers, in the later part it mentions that the platform has got on board &#8220;top quality suppliers from China with Global Manufacturer Certificate&#8221; along with &#8220;China&#8217;s leading online wholesale Marketplaces&#8221;. The document, however, does not specify who these online marketplaces are.</p>
<p>Some of the key features of the platform,  which is at the moment invitation-only, are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Wholesale prices</li>
<li>30 suppliers, of which six are international wholesalers</li>
<li>Over 8,000 product listings across electronics, lifestyle, home, auto  and kids categories</li>
<li>50 orders since launch of pilot a month back</li>
</ul>
<p>Sellers need to send an email to get an invitation to access the platform. They can then view the products, place a sample or a bulk order and make the payment. Flipkart will handle the delivery, including customs clearance. The company, in the document, states that it sells about 80,000 men&#8217;s t-shirts on its platform with an average selling price of Rs 350. The wholesale price on Flipkart Global for men&#8217;s t-shirt, the document states, is Rs 85.</p>
<p>India&#8217;s online marketplaces have recently launched a number of initiatives for their merchants. In December, <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/12/snapdeal-2015-story/" target="_blank">Snapdeal</a> launched Sherpalo, a single dashboard for merchants to access all seller related services like on-boarding, training, product listing and capital assistance. Earlier this month <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/paytm-acquires-shifu/" target="_blank">Paytm</a> launched<a href="http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/tech/tech-news/Paytm-Force-service-launched-to-assist-sellers/articleshow/50644295.cms" target="_blank"> Paytm Force</a>, which connects sellers on the marketplace with about 3,000 service providers to help in areas like catalogue, order fulfilment and account management. <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/shopclues-funding-unicorn/" target="_blank">ShopClues</a>, which just entered the coveted Unicorn club, launched an Android app for its sellers.</p>
<p>In June last year, <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/flipkart-amazon-users-dispute/" target="_blank">Amazon</a> India launched a <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/06/amazon-manufacturers-sell-globally/" target="_blank">global selling programme</a> that merchants in India to sell on Amazon.com and Amazon.co.uk to begin with. Of course the big daddy of them all is Alibaba. The platform claims to have about 4.5 million Indian SMEs on its platform. In December, Alibaba launched <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/12/alibaba-launches-services-for-indian-smes/" target="_blank">SMILE</a>, which stands for Small and Medium Industries Leveraging Export, for Indian SMEs. The programme will offer solutions like financing, logistics, certifications and technology.</p>
<h2>YourStory take</h2>
<p>As the e-commerce companies battle it out for supremacy, the focus has been on what these sites are doing to capture and retain customers. However, considering the fact that all the e-commerce players are marketplaces, gaining merchant loyalty is equally important. While ShopClues and Snapdeal have focused on getting a large number of merchants on board, Flipkart was not really playing the numbers game at least in this area. Flipkart has a base of 80,000 sellers, while Snapdeal has about two lakh merchants and ShopClues about 3.5 lakh merchants. It remains to be seen if Flipkart will change this strategy. While such initiatives, like Flipkart Global, will definitely make merchants happy, finally it all comes down to the platform which helps them make the most money and profits. Flipkart has rightly focused on the low prices that its sourcing platform offers to lure merchants as this impacts their bottom lines directly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/flipkart-global/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Myntra says on course to clock $1 billion GMV in 2016</title>
		<link>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/myntra-800-million-gmv/</link>
		<comments>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/myntra-800-million-gmv/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 14:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tarush Bhalla]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e - commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exclusively.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flipkart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jabong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Myntra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Myntra GMV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rocket Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snapdeal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voonik]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourstory.com/?p=176543</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In an announcement on Thursday, Myntra said that it had clocked an annualised Gross Merchandise Value (GMV) of $800 million in January 2016. This brings the e-commerce company one step closer to the $ 1 billion GMV target that the company will be going after in FY-2017. According to the company, there were three key strategies [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In an announcement on Thursday, Myntra said that it had clocked an annualised Gross Merchandise Value (GMV) of $800 million in January 2016. This brings the e-commerce company one step closer to the $ 1 billion GMV target that the company will be going after in FY-2017.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176546" style="width: 799px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/ATT00113.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-176546" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/ATT00113.jpg" alt="Myntra senior executives (L to R): Kalyan Krishnamurthy, CFO; Ananth Narayanan, CEO; Prasad Kompalli, Head – eCommerce Platform, Myntra" width="799" height="401" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Myntra senior executives (L to R): Sundar Prabhakar, Head- Finance ; Ananth Narayanan, CEO; Prasad Kompalli, Head – eCommerce Platform, Myntra</figcaption></figure>
<p>According to the company, there were three key strategies that helped the company reach the $800 million GMV mark. First was to focus on the brand mix and performance on its platform. By last December, the platform had over 2,000 brands on its site, 800 of which were added in 2015.</p>
<p>Secondly, the company said, good supply chain management helped it reduce cost by six percent in the last quarter. Myntra&#8217;s logistics works with eKart, the logistics arm of its parent &#8211; Flipkart. This gives it wider reach as well as ability to handle high load of deliveries during peak seasons.</p>
<p>Lastly, the company utilised technology for &#8220;intelligent discounting&#8221;, so as to not over-discount a certain product.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“It was a conscious call. We realised that there are certain styles which are more elastic, where we saw that we will optimise the discount on them, where the customer also sees value in them.” </em>says Ananth Narayanan, CEO, Myntra.</p></blockquote>
<p>This has resulted in a <strong>drop of six per cent in discounts last quarter</strong>. Ananth, however, says they will never do away with discounts.</p>
<figure id="attachment_176549" style="width: 800px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Ananth_Narayanan__CEO__Myntra_-_Copy-1.jpg"><img class="wp-image-176549 size-full" src="http://d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Ananth_Narayanan__CEO__Myntra_-_Copy-1.jpg" alt="Ananth_Narayanan, CEO, Myntra" width="800" height="399" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Ananth Narayanan, CEO, Myntra</figcaption></figure>
<p>In May 2015, Myntra made its biggest move of <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/05/myntra-app-only/" target="_blank">going app-only</a>, raising doubts and speculations on its growth. It enhanced its app, making it <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/12/new-myntra_2-0/" target="_blank">social</a> and interactive by introducing a style forum for customers to ask questions. Myntra also saw Ananth coming in as the new CEO to steer the company.</p>
<p>Amongst all those speculations, here’s a cheat sheet to how Myntra has performed:</p>
<ul>
<li>While clocking an <strong>annualised GMV of $800 million</strong>, the company has seen a <strong>70 per cent Year-on-Year growth</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Fifty-five per cent of its revenues come from Tier II cities</strong>, which also contribute to <strong>60 per cent of its overall traffic</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Myntra, till date, has <strong>11 private labels</strong>, which contributed to <strong>20 per cent of its revenue</strong>. They have <strong>more than 30 International brands</strong> on the platform, which <strong>bring in five per cent of the overall revenue</strong>.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>Its <strong>highest selling brand is also its private label Roadster</strong>, aiming to <strong>clock Rs 400 crore in 2015-16</strong> and become a Rs 650-crore ($100 million) brand by end of 2016.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>The company claims to have a <strong>monthly active user base of eight million</strong> on the app.</li>
</ul>
<p>In terms of categories, the company claims that womenswear grew by 73 per cent in 2015, while brand count for menswear went up to 419, showing a growth of almost 70 per cent.</p>
<h2><strong>YourStory take </strong></h2>
<p>In recent months, Myntra&#8217;s biggest competitor Jabong has not really been firing on all cylinders, owing to inadequate support from its backer <a href="http://yourstory.com/2016/01/rocket-internet-india/" target="_blank">Rocket Internet</a>. The multiple exits of senior officials from Jabong in the last year is indicative of the company&#8217;s issues. This has definitely worked to Myngtra&#8217;s advantage.</p>
<p>But it is still early to say whether its app-only strategy is a complete winner, with the competition scaling up from bigger e-commerce giants like Snapdeal, which recently <a href="http://yourstory.com/2015/02/snapdeal-fashion-portal-exclusively-com/" target="_blank">acquired Exclusively.com</a> to strengthen its fashion business.</p>
<p>Amazon is also really upping its game and putting the spotlight on its fashion offering, where it is providing high discounts. With so much competition, FY 2017 will be when we get to know whether Myntra’s app-only strategy has truly been successful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourstory.com/2016/01/myntra-800-million-gmv/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using memcached
Database Caching 2/5 queries in 0.002 seconds using apc
Object Caching 2006/2007 objects using apc
Content Delivery Network via Amazon Web Services: CloudFront: d152j5tfobgaot.cloudfront.net

 Served from: yourstory.com @ 2016-01-30 16:55:18 by W3 Total Cache -->